ets
ets
for
for
it
it
is
is
long
long
positive
positive
earned
earned
t
t
at
at
I
I
teacher
teacher
Is
Er
i miss
我想念
Our topic today is very delicate
我們今天的題目很細膩
Medical Imaging in the Age of Nimi
耐米時代的醫學影像
I think everyone is interested in medical imaging
我想大家對醫學影像
between our normal lives
在我們平常生活之間
Everyone's X-rayed
每個人都照過 X光
Did you take an ultrasound, what did you take?
照過超音波 照過什麼
Today we have no speakers
今天我們無講人
Gu Yu Guangyan
孤瑜光眼
He's a researcher at our nursing home
他是我們護理所的研究員
His research on video is many years
他在影像方面的研究是多年
He is going to take an X-ray image today
他今天是要以 X光的影像
But his X-ray images
不過他的 X光影像
It is higher resolution than the X-ray images we usually go to the hospital to take
要比我們平常去醫院照的 X光影像的解析度要高
Very, very much, so it's called Naimi
非常非常多 所以叫做耐米
He'll let us know how good his resolution is then
他到時候會告訴我們他的解析度有多好
And it's a 3D space
而且是 3度空間的
Then introduce our keynote speaker today
那介紹一下我們今天主講人
Dr. Hu joined the Academia Sinica in 1992
胡博士是 1992 年進入中央研究院
So I'm still two years old
所以到現在也有二歲
He is the physics department of National Taiwan University
他是臺灣大學的物理系
Graduated in 1982
在 1982 年畢業的
Then in Connecta and Wisconsin in the United States
然後在美國的 Connecta 跟 Wisconsin
Ph.D.
分別拿到碩博士
Then he was actually doing his Ph.D.
然後他其實在做博士期間
synchrotron radiation
就是以同步輻射
Let me introduce Taiwan by the way
我順便介紹臺灣
There is also a nice synchrotron radiation
也有一個很好的同步輻射
facilities in Hsinchu
的設施在新竹
this is who we do the research on
這是我們做研究的人
very lucky place
很有福氣的地方
Dr. Hu used the synchrotron radiation in Hsinchu
胡博士就是利用新竹的同步輻射
I believe he has a lot of images today
我相信他今天有蠻多的影像之從
Synchrotron Radiation Facility in Hsinchu
新竹的同步輻射的設施做出來
Of course, in terms of synchrotron radiation
當然在同步輻射來講
There are many facilities in the world
這是全世界各有不少的設施
So Dr. Hu is everywhere
所以胡博士也是到處
Go to Europe and America
歐洲也去 美國也去
Many places are his experimental sites
很多地方都是他的實驗場所
Then he probably
那他今天大概
I don't know what to say in detail
我不知道詳細要講什麼
However, it can be seen from the title
不過大概從題目可以看到
sometimes he tells us today
有時候他今天會告訴我們
what technique does he use
他用什麼樣子的技術
Can make an image very clear
可以把一個影像做到非常的清晰
Then he did research recently
那最近他做研究
Also do some biological in vivo
還做一些生物體的in vivo
It's just some images of the living body
就是活體的一些影像
I don't know if he will give me today
我不知道他今天會不會給我
his research work
他的研究工作
It is also very prominent in this
在這方面也非常的突出
then i talk nonsense
那我廢話說
So let Dr. Hu begin
所以就請胡博士開始
Thank you Vice President
謝謝副院長
The vice president is memorized by our teacher
副院長是我們的老師背的
so we are happy today
所以我們高興今天
He said he was a freshman at Academia Sinica and had just arrived
他說他是中研院的新生剛剛來
with him in the hospital
跟他在院
He said we are happy today
他說我們高興今天
I was introduced by Teacher Wang
我是由王老師幫我介紹
At the same time, I also thank you very much
同時我也很謝謝感謝各位
listen at this dinner time
在這個晚飯的時候來聽
When I was next to this TOM
我當初接下來這個TOM的時候
In fact, I didn't think about it at all.
其實沒有完全沒有想
I think it is
覺得啊呀就是
Later I saw this barrier
後來看到這個這個鎮障
I find again
我再發覺
so i put my 101 suit
所以我把我的101套西裝
Where can I find hope
有哪弄出來希望
Everyone will feel better
大家心裡會感覺比較好一點
ok good
OK好
Then what my teacher Wang said just now is
那我那個剛剛王老師講的是
I probably will today
我今天大概都會
I will talk a little bit
都會稍微講一下
look at everyone's time
看看大家的時間
OK
OK
OK what I'm going to say is
OK 我要講的就是
Methical Imaging
Methical Imaging
Metical Imaging This is when I was going to talk about this
Methical Imaging 這個是我本來要講這個的時候
I was thinking of saying I'm going to make my own stuff
我本來想的是說我要做我自己的東西的話
I will say X-ray microscopy
我就會講說是 X-ray microscopy
or
或者是
But I happened to be in Europe at the time
但是我那時候我正好在歐洲
I used to be TeeSus Advisor
我以前TeeSus Advisor
I'll just talk to him, talk about a Public Talk
我就跟他講 講一個Public Talk
And he's like, oops, he's going to give this talk to the public, science talk
然後他就說 哎呀 他是要對大眾講這個演講科學演講
Speaking speeches, the simplest way to say eleven is that you tell them to make money
講演講 最簡單講個十一個就是你告訴他們賺錢
The second is to take care of the body according to how they do
第二個就是照他們怎麼樣照顧身體
I said make money, otherwise I can't teach
我說賺錢我可不然沒辦法教
Then I will talk about a topic related to taking care of the body.
那我就講一個題目 跟照顧身體有關係
But what we're actually doing is classifying
但是我們做的其實是歸類
A lot of what we have done in recent years is about Mechanical Research
我們最近幾年做的很多是關於Methical Research
But how to take care of your body
但是跟要怎麼樣照顧自己的身體
It doesn't really matter
其實沒有太大的關係
put up business images
生意影像放起來
I think everyone will be interested
我想大家多少就會有興趣
Another catch word
另外一個 catch word
This is the fancy word
就是這個是 fancy word
It's Nano
就是奈米
I think everyone has been nami
我想大家已經被奈米
It's been bombing for ten years
已經轟炸了十代年了
So you probably want to say
所以你們大概也會想說
What does Nano have to do with us?
奈米到底跟我們有什麼關係
I said for business
我就說針對生意
So I won't talk too much about business images today
所以我今天不會講太多的生意影像
I don't care about MRI stuff
我講不管MRI這些東西
Actually like now you are on Wikipedia
其實像現在你在 Wikipedia上面
You can find many similar reports wherever you look.
隨便找都可以看到很多類似的報圖
So I think my main job today
所以我想我今天主要的工作
Just to talk about the relationship between business images and Nano
就是要講說生意影像跟奈米的關係
Business images are of course important
生意影像當然很重要
I think I don't need to talk about this
我想這個我就不用再講了
So I gave a very simple
所以我給了一個非常簡單的
The first one is an important diagnostic tool
第一個它是很重要的診斷工具
now you go to the hospital
現在你到醫院去
especially in the last ten years
尤其最近十年以來
you go to the hospital
你到醫院去
we say we don't know
我們說不知道是
Doctors hardly diagnose
現在醫生幾乎都不太診斷
if you have anything
你如果有什麼事
Remember to queue you for all the tests when he goes in
他進去記得先排你做所有的 test
after finishing
做完了以後
in the current doctor
在現在的醫生
many young doctors
很多年輕的醫生
you if he didn't do these things
你如果他如果沒有做這些准斷
I'm afraid he has no way to see the evidence.
他恐怕沒有辦法很難看證
It is also said
這也是代表說
Now these advances in medical imaging
現在這些醫療影像的進步
to a degree
要照一個程度
so i'll talk a little bit later
所以我等一下會講一些
S light here
S光這邊的
I know better
我自己比較清楚
some of his previous history
他一些以前的歷史
you will find
你會發覺
Actually so many of us are doing
其實我們這麼多人在做
It's not useless on weekdays
平日並不是沒有用
Today everyone can enjoy
今天大家可以享受到
This better medical care
這個比較好的醫療照顧
With the development of this business image
跟這個生意影像的發展
has a great relationship
是有絕大的關係的
I am at this time
我在這時候
Let me talk about this topic first
我先把這題目就先講
This business video and unreasonable technology
這生意影像跟難理科技
what does it matter
到底有什麼關係
this is
這個是
Let's say the first thing is to say
我們講第一個就是說
Due to the development of unreasonable technology
因為難理科技的發展
in business images
在生意影像裡面
We have created new imaging principles
我們有造成新的成像原理
this i will talk about now
這我現在會講
we can't do it now
我們沒有辦法現在
go to particular example
去特別的例子
But this is an important reason
但是這個是一個重要的原因
It's because you have a future that is difficult to understand technology
就是因為你有難理科技的以後
Your previous imaging method
你以前這個成像方式
you can do it differently
你可以用不同的方式去做
you will get better
你會得到更好的
Then of course it means
然後當然就是說
Have better components and equipment
有更好的元件跟設備
So parts of these
所以這些的部分
I'll ask again later
我等一下會再問一下
Research done by myself
自己比較做的research
i will tell you
我會跟大家講
you may use
你可能用
I'll just say I use X-rays as an example
我就說我用X光來做例子說
what do these things mean
這些東西是什麼意思
OK
OK
Why can technology be difficult
為什麼可以難以科技
Why does this new imaging principle
為什麼會造成新的這個成像原理
And it can be used to make better original parts and equipment
而且可以用來做更好的原件跟設備
but one important point
但是很重要的一點
so it's like business
所以就跟生意一樣
The most relevant is actually
最有關聯的其實是
first lead technique or called contrast technique
先引技或者叫做對比技
or calibration
或者是叫做標定
The noun is not very uniform
這個名詞並沒有太統一
but basically
但是基本上
It is how you use the extra substance
就是你怎麼樣使用外加的這個物質
Make it this image imaging can do better
讓它這個影像成像可以做得更好
Well, that's why my main connection today is with Nelly.
那其實所以我今天主要的跟耐理的關聯
In fact, it is on the Naili line
其實就是在耐理線
That is to say, for other biomedical images
就是說對其他的生物醫學的這個影像來講
Nai Li Xian Yin Ji
就是耐理顯引技
Why should it be
耐理顯引技它為什麼要
we need to use nelly
我們要用耐理
Don't use the traditional way
不用以前傳統來這種
There must be a lot of different techniques
就有一定很多各種各樣的顯引技
for different image formats
針對不同的影像方式
its important features
那它重要的特性
The first one is Nelly
第一個就是耐理裡面
The only reason for it is that its size is important
它的唯一的理由就是它的大小是很重要的
You need to be able to reach a reasonable size
你要能夠達到耐理的大小
then i want everyone to know
那我想大家知道
should now be the size
現在應該大小
Everyone knows how small Naimi is
大家都知道耐米是多小
Nimi is 1000 times smaller than Pooh
耐米就是比維尼還要再小1000倍
Pooh is 1000 times smaller than Haomi
維尼又比豪米再小1000倍
a very simple
一個很簡單的
The size of the gills that the human body perceives
人體有感知的這個腮大小
It's actually Homi
其實是豪米
homi's words
豪米的話
Pooh
維尼
Sorry
Sorry
hehehehe
呵呵呵呵
Ok
Ok
so your hair is
所以你的頭髮是
Micron is Haomi or
micron是豪米還是
Oh ok
喔 ok
Hair is say 80micron
頭髮是譬如說80micron
it's pooh
就是維尼
about
左右
You can think of this Naimi
你可以想這個耐米的話
1000 times smaller than this
就比這個再小1000倍
so i wait
所以我等一下
we used to do a
我們以前做過一個
one
一個
Um
嗯
very short lead is given
很短的lead is gave
Absolutely not
完全沒有
us
我們
I am today when I was in Korea
我今天我有年在韓國的時候
At that time, South Korean President Oh Moo-hyun visited
那時候韓國總統吳武軒去參觀
the single track over there
那邊的single track
That
那
They told our cooperation team
他們就給我們的合作的這個team說
he only listens to one head
他只聽一個頭
not three and a half
不要三分半
He said how do you tell him
他說你要怎麼樣跟他講
so we talked
所以我們就講了
made a
做了一個
This animation is easy to say
這個動畫很容易就是說
you shut it off from you
你從你去關的
I keep seeing this space in the middle of you
一直看到你這個中間的這個空間
how big is the gap
這個間隙有多大
we start with a
我們就從一隻
From a human to mouse to mouse
從一個人開始到小鼠到小鼠的
This one organ mouse
這個一個器官的小鼠
How many cells are in an organ
器官裡面有多少細胞
how big is the cell
細胞它有多大
Then how many cells have
然後多大細胞裡面有
all the way down to the molecular structure
一路下去到分子的結構
You know the scale of this
你就知道這個的scale
this difference in the middle
這個中間的這個差異
is very very large
是非常非常大
So after looking at it like this
所以它這樣看了以後
it just feels like
它才有感覺說
no good then what's the matter with you
不好那你是怎麼回事
or say for it under the microscope
或者說對它在顯微鏡下
You don't even realize how small it is
你其實都沒有感覺是它有多小
The other nano
那另外一個這個奈米的
It is the developer
它這個顯影器就是
The most important thing is probably to use particles
最主要大概就是用顆粒
Or some of these particles from oil machines
或者一些油機的這種顆粒
its composition
那它的組成
is that I can use many different ways
就是我可以用很多不同方式
let this one
讓這一顆
Although a very small particle
雖然很小很小的一顆顆粒
It's probably hundreds of atoms
它的可能都是幾百個原子
or thousands of atoms
或者幾千個原子
But on top there will be different composition
但在上面還會有不同的組成
And then there's the surface of it
然後再來就是它的表面
That is to say when you were so young
就是說你在這麼小的時候
its surface takes up its nature
它的表面占了它的性質
very significant portion
非常重大的部分
So we say its surface modification
所以我們說它的表面的修飾
or surface this
或表面的這個
This presentation will cause his characteristic
這個呈現就會造成他的特性
big difference
很大的這個不一樣
What does his nano-developer do?
那他的奈米顯影機要做的事
Of course he can be the best first
當然第一個他能夠最好
Ability to Reconnect with Metabolism
能夠再跟代謝的關係
means you can
就是說你能夠
The second is that you can exclude
第二個是你能夠排除
because you want to say
因為你是要譬如說
You are going to have an MRI
你要做MRI
Or when doing HRA
或者是要做HRA的時候
he will call you
他會給你打
So the video camera goes in
所以顯影機進去
Then of course you hope he doesn't stay
那你當然希望他不要留在
because it's not a good thing
因為不是好東西
You certainly don't need to stay in the body
你當然不需要留在身體
So his exclusion is also very important
所以他的排除這也是非常重要
and now say for example
然後現在譬如說
you want to do functional development
你要做功能性的顯影
is what I hope or is a manifestation of this molecule
就是我希望或者是這個分子的顯影
what you wish you typed in
你希望你打進去的東西
He will run where you want to grow
他會跑到你想要去長的地方
So the professionalism of his organization is also important
所以他的組織的專業性也很重要
and now there is a trend
然後現在有一個趨勢
that is to say I now wish
就是說我現在希望
No I can now use different mods
不要我現在能夠用不同的模組
Now everyone's every mod has been done
現在大家的每個模組都已經做了
The module is to image an MRI
模組就是影像一個MRI
Magnetic shock photos of SPAC positron and MRI
SPAC這個正子跟MRI的磁震照片
how do you put it together
那你要怎麼樣把它放在一起
you don't want to say
那你不希望是說
I get a shot while I do this
我做這個的時候打一針
You sit and wait until after a few images
你坐在等到做了幾個影像以後
this person
這個人
almost
已經差不多了
So we hope that means
所以我們希望就是說
This is the best time
這個是能夠最好是一次
Let this patient suffer less from this pain
讓這個病人少受一些這個痛苦
So it becomes an optical module imaging
所以變成光模組成像
It is also an important nano-developer
也是奈米顯影劑一個重要的
the direction of this development
這個發展的方向
In fact, I think
那其實裡面我自己覺得
That is to say, nano developer
就是說奈米顯影劑
There is one most important Foundation
有一個最重要的Foundation
this is what we think
這個是我們覺得
this is a cartoon
這個是一個卡通
get it out
弄出來是說
was supposed to explain
本來是要講解
It means this Tumor and this Angiogenesis
是說這個Tumor跟這個Angiogenesis
Tumor is tumor
Tumor就是腫瘤
This is when a tumor grows
這個在長出腫瘤的時候
Blood vessels will have
血管會有
we will now
我們現在今天會
I'm talking about a very important topic
我講很重要的一個題目
Is the senior of blood vessels
就是血管的資深
or neovascularization
或者微血管的新生
when the tumor grows
就當腫瘤長的時候
this was long ago
這個很早以前
twenty or thirty years ago
在二三十年前
There was a doctor named Judah Fogman
有一個醫生叫Judah Fogman
he does open up
他做開刀開裂
The tumor he operated on
他開刀的這個腫瘤
He found that the tumor
他發覺這個腫瘤上面
normal blood vessel density
通常的血管的密度
will be much higher than normal tissue
都會比正常的組織高很多
his idea is to say
他的想法就是說
Because these tumors are rapidly growing
因為這些腫瘤是快速成長
he hopes
他希望
He wants to be able to have a lot of nutrients
他希望能夠有大量的養分
oxygen to supply him
氧氣來供應他
He grows up so fast
他這樣好快速成長
So he sent out a bunch of distress calls
所以他就送出一大堆求救的訊號
call these blood vessels say
叫這些血管說
You send a tube now
你現在趕快送一個管子過來
oxygenate it
把它這個氧起來
that's because of this
那就是因為這個
So it will cause our nanometer today
所以會造成我們今天奈米這個
Whether this particle is used for treatment
這個顆粒不管是它來做治療
Or to do a very important basis for visualization
或者來做顯像一個非常重要的基礎
today otherwise you can think about it
今天否則你可以想想說
Why should I use nanoparticles
我為什麼要用奈米顆粒
molecule of this drug
分子的這個藥物
or molecular imaging agent
或者分子的顯像劑
can do the same why
一樣可以做為什麼
It's this specificity these could be better
它的這個專一性這些可能會更好
Then I think the most important difference is the nanoparticles
那我覺得最重要的差別就是奈米顆粒
it has this sex
它有這個性
That is to say, I treat my blood vessel as
就是說我當我這個血管
I'll keep emphasizing later
我等一下後面會一直在強調
this blood vessel it
這血管它
The new blood vessels grow very broken
新生的血管它長得很破碎
its structure is not very complete
它的結構不是很完整
So it becomes you now in the middle
所以就變成你現在中間裡面
This has particles in it
這個有顆粒在裡面
it will run out
它會跑出去
In fact, you can be on the Internet
本來其實你可以在網路上
If you go to find this called EPR
你如果去找這個叫做EPR
Infactor
Infactor
Enhanced Permeation and Retention
Inhance Perneation and Retention
give it to improve its penetration
給它提高它的穿透
Follow up function
跟保持的功能
have it this blood vessel
有它這個血管
particle This particle will run out
particle這個粒子會跑出去
you know after running out
跑出去以後你知道
Particles are not the same as this molecule
粒子跟這個分子不一樣
It stays there after running out
跑出去以後它就待在那裡
It's not easy to come back smoothly
它不太容易再順的回來
So at this point you can
所以在這個時候你就可以
we have many studies
我們有很多study
you can see it turn
你可以看到它轉
After putting this thing in
把這個東西進去以後
its in you if you have a tumor
它在你如果有一個腫瘤
The blood vessels over there are very broken.
那邊的血管非常破碎
been leaking
一直在漏
like you want to turn on a faucet
就像你想開個水龍頭
There's a leak all over you
你整個可是有一個地方在漏水
it just keeps leaking
它就一直漏
There will be a lot of water at the end
到最後的地方水就會很多
So this can be done
所以這就可以拿來做
This tumor-resistant drug
這個耐瘤的藥物
or tumor-resistant adenitis
或者是耐瘤的腺炎
today we are very simple
就今天我們很簡單
it means i want to see the stream
就是說我想要看到種流
You said I typed something in
你說我打一個東西進去
it will stay there
它會留在那裡
I just need to detect in this body
我只要去偵測在這個身體裡面
where is there a lot of this
哪個地方有很多這個
then i'm one
那我這就是一個
Can hear clearly with microphone
可以用microphone聽得清楚
Huh? There is a microphone
咦?microphone有啊
should be open
應該是開了
right
對
OK
可以吧
OK too high
OK 太高了
OK good
OK 好
That
那
OK so this part is
OK 所以這個部分就是說
with this nano
跟這個奈米的這個
That is to say, the medicine behind nano
就是說後面奈米的醫學
In fact, there is a major relationship
其實有重大的關係
that is
就是說
The tumor angiogenesis
這個腫瘤血管新生
would cause this to be different from normal this
會造成這有跟正常的這個
where the organization is different
組織不一樣的地方
so that you can have this specificity
這樣你才可以有這個特異性
And this is a
而這是一個
What we replace is to say
我們取代的就是說
you can see that is to say
你可以看到就是說
I had a small one here
我這邊當初有一個很小的這個
cancer cells clump together
癌細胞團聚在一起
when it starts to turn into a tumor
它開始要變成腫瘤的時候
it will flow from this artery
它就會從這個動脈
or venous
或者靜脈各的
let them grow these blood vessels
各讓他們長出這些血管來
provide it with nutrients
提供它這邊的養分
OK
OK
That's the same as this example
那像這也是一樣的這個例子
then we are talking now
那我們現在在講
In this common way of medical imaging
就常見的這個醫學影像的方式
There are a few that I can't introduce one by one
有幾個我沒有辦法一一介紹
but basically they
但是基本上他們
In fact, I just said that if you classify
其實我剛講你如果歸類
to this
到這個的話
The principles are very similar
原理都很相近
Just my first one I ever need to have a thing to go
就是我第一個我都需要有一個東西去
to where you want to see
到你想要看的地方
For example, in the way of this single-gloss paper
比如像這個單光紙的方式的話
This is using a
這個是使用一個
You put a substance of this radiation
你放一個這個放射線的物質
hit into the body
打到身體裡面去
This radioactive material emits this
這個放射線物質在裡面發出這個
This GAMRAID
這個GAMRAID
at this time you outside
這時候你外面
If there is a GAMRAID camera
如果有一個GAMRAID的camera
you can take
你就可以照
Tell me if this camera can take pictures
說我如果這個camera可以照出
where did it come from
它從哪裡出來的
Then it might have some
那它上面也許會帶一些
bring some products
帶些的產物啊
Or it has a special calibration function
或者是說它有特別的標定的這個功能
then you can see where it's staying
那你就可以看到它在哪一個地方待著
or how it will be brought
或者它會被帶些的狀況怎麼樣
You will achieve the role of this visualization
你就會達到這個顯影的作用
That or the positron way
那或者是正子方式
The positron method means using a positron
正子方式是說用一個正子
It will be I-Mate
它會被I-Mate
will be wiped out
會被消滅
It's this Zhengzi and this
就是這個正子跟這個
are positively charged electrons
是正代正電的電子
Is a
是一個
if it collides with electrons
它跟電子碰在一起的話
It will generate about 500KV or so of this
它會產生大概500KV左右的這個
This GAMRAID
這個GAMRAID
it's in there
那它在裡面
because it is gone after
因為它被消失了以後
Just release this GAMRAID
就放出這個GAMRAID
GAMRAID it will generate
GAMRAID它會產生
I've been walking in the lazy direction since I was a kid
我從小懶的方向走
So I grab these two from the entity
所以我從實體抓到這兩個
The words of this Gamma Ray of this Gamma Ray
這個Gamma Ray的這個Gamma射線的話
I just draw a line
我就畫一條線
I know where your stuff comes from
我就知道你這個東西從哪裡出來
That's the way to know where your stuff is
就用這種方式來知道你這些東西在哪裡
produced
產生的
Those things are not human
那這些東西都不是人理裡面的
It's something you typed in
它這個東西是你打進去的
So when you go to the hospital
所以你們去醫院的時候
If the doctor tells you this time
如果醫生叫你這時候
You'd better ask if it's necessary
你最好問一下是有沒有必要
Because doctors don't want to deal with these things themselves.
因為這些東西醫生自己都不願意處理
It's all radioactive
它這個這些都是有放射性
Although its half-life may be short
雖然它的半衰期可能很短
like two days or three days
比如兩天或三天
so i tried this
所以我想這個
Every medical image
這個每一個醫學影像
it has its very important role
它都有它非常重大的作用
But every side effect it must fall below it
但是每一個它一定跌破它的副作用
So I guess it means
所以我想就是說
most doctors he is not too
大部分的醫生他不是太
i'm not saying there's something wrong with the doctor
我不是說醫生有問題
Rather, the system now
而是說現在這個系統
like my father
譬如說像我父親
He wants everyone their age
他要每一個他們年紀大的人
He likes to look like Shopping
他喜歡像Shopping一樣去看
he is in a different hospital
他在不同的醫院
Come to the hospital here to have a look
到這邊醫院看一看
he felt unhappy he went to the inner courtyard
他覺得不高興他到內院去
But if you go to this one today
可是如果今天去這一家
He asks you to be a CT
他就叫你做一個CT
That family asked you to be a CT again
那一家又叫你做一個CT
this one in Taiwan
台灣的這個
Not registered on your health insurance card
你的健保卡上並沒有登記
So you end up finding yourself doing it multiple times a year
所以你最後發覺一年你做了好多次
No matter how safe he says it is
那這個不管他講的再安全
You still end up with radiation damage
你最後你還是會受到輻射損傷
then we used to have a
那我們以前有一個
Academician of the American Academy of Sciences told us
美國科學院院士他跟我們講
That is to say, this kind of sixty or seventy-year-old
就是說到了這種六七十歲
He said that we all check another Mutation
他說我們都是再查一個Mutation
will get cancer
就會得Cancer
One Mutation around
One Mutation around
So it has better be careful
So it has better be careful
Then let me say this, for example,
那我下面譬如說這個裡面
to me just finished
對我剛剛講完
here for example
這裡面譬如說
Ultrasound this is now
超音波這個現在是
Recognized as the least damaged
公認這個損傷最少的
So many people now think that ultrasound
所以超音波現在有很多人認為
Said that the ultrasound will be better and better
說超音波他會越做越好
He will probably replace most of this medical imaging
他可能會取代大部分的這種醫療影像
That benevolent care is also a very Pobby
那慈政照應也是一個非常Pobby
But benevolent care has one of the biggest problems
但是慈政照應有一個最大的問題
For example like my dad he has this Pace Maker
比如說像我父親他有這個Pace Maker
have this starter
有這個起鍋器
he can't do it
他就不能做
Then X-ray does not have this problem
那X-ray是沒有這個問題
but x-ray wait a minute i'll talk
但是X-ray等一下我會講
it's his pity
就是他可惜的
He will also have this radioactive
他也會有這個放射性的
The problem of radiation damage
這個輻射傷害的問題
Then you can this picture is us
那你可以這個圖是我們
I copy down
我copy下來
that is to say basically
就是說基本上講說
every image of you
你每一個成像
His Limit degree
他的這個Limit度
with his resolution
跟他的這個解析度
it's all
它都是
so you might just say
所以你可能就說
what do i need to see
我需要看什麼樣的東西
What kind of video mode do I want to use
我要用什麼樣的這個影像方式
that's very important
那這是很重要的
I have a few pictures here
那我這邊有幾個圖
I won't talk about it one by one
我就不一一講
That's basically this
那這就是基本上是這個
you went to the hospital
你們去了醫院
when you put it in
就放進去的時候
you probably know this
你大概就知道這個
For example, he is now afraid that you
比如說他現在你恐怕你
If you don't ask you can't figure it out
如果不問你根本搞不清楚
is he masago or spac
他是正子還是spac
or mri
還是mri
Anyway, it's the same as going into a hole
反正都是一樣進去一個洞
and tell you to sit over there
然後叫你坐在那邊
kind of good
那種好
and put you in later
然後把你放進去以後
Doctors just ran away
醫生就通通跑光了
like positron emission because it's a radioactive substance
像正子放射,因為它是一個放射性的物質
So it needs an accelerator to be able to produce this kind of isodigit
所以它要有一個加速器才能夠製造這種同位數
Ultrasound now also has a lot of progress
超音波現在也有很多進展
For example, basically it talks about the three-dimensional space
譬如說基本上它就講這個三度空間的
They even talk about ultrasound in the fourth dimension
甚至它們要講四度空間的超音波
Then I don't care about it
那我這邊就不計議想
Basically it means that it gives you the same thing that you can say it
基本上就是說它給你可以譬如說它同一個東西
In the past, for example, we said that you want to see this pregnant woman
以前我們譬如說你要看這個懷孕的婦女
You have to see her child, she is in the clouds, you will see a look
你要看她小孩,她在雲中,你會看到一個樣子
It is possible now, that is to say, it can be viewed from three angles at the same time
現在可以,就是說同時給你從三個角度來看
These are big improvements
這些都是蠻大的進步
There is one for ultrasound, and I borrowed this from a research friend of ours.
超音波有一個,我這個是我跟我們一個合作的研究朋友借的
That is, one of them has something to do with ultrasound and treatment
就是它們有一個跟超音波跟治療有一點關係
It's inside the micro-explosion they use ultrasonic waves
就是它們用超音波的微爆裡面
with whether it's the gene, the gene they need to deliver or the drug
帶著不管是基因,它們需要輸送的基因或者是藥
and ultrasonically blast this micro cannon to shatter it
然後用超音波把這個微炮把它震碎
This is a normal process
這個是很正常的一個process
But because of this shattering
但是因為這個震碎的時候
Sometimes the first of many people is to say
有時候第一個很多人就是說
It can actually be used to treat cancer
其實可以用這個來治療癌症
That is because when you sleep
就是說因為你症睡的時候
this his this shockwave
這個的他的這個這個shockwave
When he was broken
就他這個破的時候
this power is great
這個力量是很大
because I remember that in
因為我記得就是說在
when they said the earliest
他們在說最早的時候
at the time of World War I
在一次大戰的時候
The propeller of the ship they found
那個他們發覺那個輪船的那個螺旋槳
often breaks
經常會破壞
easily damaged
很容易就受損
It took him a long time to know that
那他花了很長的時間才知道說
So it was your propeller that went out
原來是你那個螺旋槳出去
You have that blister when the blister pops
你有那個水泡那個水泡爆掉的時候
His strength is very great
他那個的力量是非常大的
You can hit this movement on this metal
可以在這個金屬上面打出這個動來
So they then said
所以他們後來就是說
I will improve
我再改進
So don't create so many bubbles
所以就不要產生這麼多的氣泡
So this force of this bubble
所以這氣泡的這個力量
That is to say, when we were actually making videos in the past,
就是說我們其實以前在做影像的時候
hope to catch him
希望能夠抓到他的
the first one he was very fast
第一個他的速度非常快
It's him you and us become one ex
就是他你我們這個成一個前
Saw this a while ago
前一個時段還看到這個
Suddenly he disappeared
忽然一下他就不見了
he exploded
他爆掉了
At this time he produced this position
那這個時候他產生這個位置
they are called shockwave
他們叫shockwave
just like this is not normal
就是像這種不是一般的
his this will not
他的這個就不會
Its spread these are not the same
它的這個傳播這些都不太一樣
So it will be very lethal to this cell
所以它對於這個細胞會有很大的殺傷力
especially small ones
特別是小的
The other way is after I put the genuine goods
那另外一方式就我把正貨以後
words near it
在它附近的話
It is very possible that what I have on the inside
我這裡面上面帶的東西就有很可能
Enter this cell to achieve the purpose you want
進到這個細胞裡面達到你要的這個目的
Then this is ultrasound, which is related to this
那這是超音波就是跟這個有一個
useful place
有作用的地方
You can see that the MRI is basically the same.
那磁震噪影大概你可以看到基本上也是這個樣子
Then people here he wants
然後人的在這邊他要
For example, when you want to be the head
譬如說你要做頭的時候
He's gonna fix your head
他就要把你頭固定住
Then this you can see images like this
那這個你可以看到像這個的影像
That is to say, the biggest advantage of MRI is that
就是說MRI它最大的好處就是
It is actually beneficial to soft tissue
它對軟組織其實是有
Because it is mainly to image this clear
因為它是主要是要image這個清
As long as you want it to be where there is water, it can
就你要這樣有水的地方它就可以
Then of course it has many other variations
那它當然有很多其他的變化
There are functional MRI
有人家functional MRI
diffuse MRI
diffuse MRI
It's anyway or you mix this developer differently
它反正或者是你配合不同的這個顯影劑
Doing it can do great imaging
去做它可以做到很好的影像
that MRI and it's not very accessible
那MRI而且它對親入性有不高
It's just that the damage to human nature is not high.
就是對人性的損傷不高
Of course sometimes you still have to apply developer
它當然有時候你還是要打顯影劑
the developer
這個顯影劑
Everyone says that this is passed by the food hygiene in the United States.
大家都說這個是美國這個食品衛生通過的
but you play too much
但是你去打多了
you will feel uncomfortable
你自己會覺得不舒服
OK
OK
So this is an MRI
所以這個是MRI
So now I use very very Popular
所以現在用的是非常非常Popular
But there is a problem with MRI relative
但是MRI相對有一個問題
it's because it's still expensive
就是它因為它現在還是很貴
So if you go, if the health insurance does not pay
所以說你如果去如果健保沒有給付的話
For example, now someone is
比如說現在有人在
Just want to do this with MRI
就希望用MRI做這個
breast design
乳房的設計
Then if you do X-ray in general, it may be covered by health insurance
那你在一般做X-ray的可能是健保有給付
But if the MRI is not paid for
但是這個MRI做的沒有給付的話
It might cost you 20,000 yuan to do it once
你做一次可能要花兩萬塊
Of course there are considerable benefits
那當然是有相當的好處
But even that probably isn't
但是就是說可能也不是
This image that will become the front line
會變成第一線的這種影像
Then I just said that this is an example I gave
那我剛剛就講這是我舉了一個例子
because i think of nanodiamonds
因為我想到奈米鑽石
Our Zhonglian Rag has a very strong this
我們這個中聯Rag有一個非常強的這個
I really have this team that has done a good job
非常有這個做得很好的這個team
They're making nanodiamonds
他們在做奈米鑽石
nano diamonds you put some of these on
奈米鑽石你上面帶上一些這些
These materials you want to attach
你要附加的這些材料
it has some faith in itself
它本身就有一些持信
It can also be used as a tool for confidence imaging
它可以也拿來做持信造影的工具
I'm going to find this
我去找這個
I originally wanted to talk to this licensed radiography and Naimi
我本來就想說找跟這個持證造影跟耐米
what is the relationship
有什麼關係
Except for this developing machine
除了這個顯影機以外
Later I found out that they said
後來我發覺找到他們說
You can do Naimi licensed radiography
可以做耐米持證造影
I went to see this paper
我去看這個paper
Said it can do 70 resistance meters
說它可以做到70耐米
I think that's a big deal
我想那這樣不得了
after that
那這樣子以後
Only then did he realize that they were not
結果他才發覺原來他們不是
They're here to look at the surface
他們是在這看表面的
It is increased or decreased by this
它是用這個增減
with AFM
用AFM的方式
For example, this Tommy Force Microscope
譬如說這個Tommy Force Microscope
With a very shoulder this scene
用一個很肩的這個景
and then be able to swipe across the surface
然後能夠在表面上掃
because it is very local
因為它在很局物的
Give it a very strong field
給它一個很強的這個field
or gradient
或gradient
it can cause MRI-like
它就可以造成像是MRI的
This has the same effect as this licensed radiography
這樣的這個持證造影一樣的效果
So this has nothing to do with medical imaging
所以這個跟醫療影像
probably nothing
可能是毫無關係
even images of living things
甚至連生物的影像
I'm afraid it will be difficult
恐怕都很難
then i won't talk
那我就不來講
then ourselves
那我們自己
team of friends cooperating inside
合作的朋友團隊裡面
We have a Spec with MicroCT and PAC at the National Institutes of Health
我們在國衛院有一個Spec跟MicroCT跟PAC
these three put together
這三個合在一起
it's my machine
就是我這一個機器
just one hole
就一個洞
you don't do three holes
你不要做三個洞
a round this
一個圓形的這個
then just be a mouse
然後只是做小鼠
its a small hole
它很小的一個洞
After securing the mice and sending them over
把小鼠固定好送過去以後
You can do Spec at the same time
你可以同時做Spec
Then also get this PAC
然後也可以得到這個PAC
Also get CT
也可以得到CT
we are here
我們在這邊
I'm learning from this example now
我現在就學取這個例子
This team basically hopes to develop different
這個team基本上就是希望發展不同的這種
radio isotope
radio isotope
The radio isotope is already known to be very fixed
那radio isotope其實都已經知道很固定
what are they doing
他們在做什麼
it just said
它就說
please get different antibodies
拜你上不同的抗體
or a different molecule
或者是不同的分子
so that it can selectively go where
讓它可以有選擇性的到什麼地方
different places
不同的地方
Then use the line that measures against it this way
然後再用靠著量它這個方式的線
to know where it is
去知道它在什麼地方
I won't go into detail about this part
這個部分我就不仔細講
Because this is probably a few pictures I can show
因為這個大概是我可以秀的幾個圖
It's a mouse
就是小鼠
you can see what i typed in
你可以看到我打進去的東西
you just know
你就知道
That is to say, this may be in the heart
就是說這個是可能是在這個心臟部分
you just know it's gonna come here
你只知道它會跑到這裡來
This is this image of this
這個是這個影像的這個
clearer like this
比較清楚的像這個
You can see like this SPECT image
你可以看到像這SPECT image
it looks at this radial isotope
它看這個radial isotope
this is radioactive
這個是放射性的
After this is added, it has a special function
這個上面加上去了以後就是它有特別的功能
You can see something like this actually outside of this
你可以看到像一些其實外面的這個
Neither is SPECT
都不是SPECT
These skeletons outside are actually made of X-ray
這個外面這些骨架其實是X-ray做的
Its SPECT index will tell you
它這個SPECT的指數會告訴你
Where are these things you will light up
你會發亮的這些東西在什麼位置
This skeleton is just to let you know
這個骨架只是讓你知道
where do you take the mouse
你帶看哪裡的小鼠
These are probably images of SPECT
這些大概都是SPECT的image
OK, I will finish my general introduction
OK,我就講完我的general介紹
For File
對於File
It's like a doctor's hospital
就是醫生醫院這樣
Now I'm going to talk about what I did
現在要做講我自己做的
Of course when you do it yourself
那當然自己做的時候
I must say that the previous ones are not good.
一定要講前面的都不好
right? I did it myself.
對不對 就自己做的
Otherwise why would I do it right?
否則我就幹嘛做對不對
good first thing
那第一件事好
I'm going to say now that I do X-ray
我現在就要講我是做X-ray的
Because the vice president just said
因為剛剛這個副院長已經講
I've been doing it since I started
我一直從我開始做
This is where the research begins
這做研究開始
I'm in synchrotron radiation
我就是在同步輻射
So that's why I got synchrotron radiation
所以就是我出了同步輻射
I can't do anything else
我別的什麼東西都不會做
So that synchrotron radiation
所以那同步輻射
is that it produces a lot of light
就是它產生很多光
We just can't do every light
我們就是不能每個光都做
we did x-ray
我們就做了X光
X-ray it's just saying
X光它的就是說
with these other
跟其他的這些
i don't mean it per se
我不是說它本身
with these other blue pens
跟其他的這些藍筆
what good is it
它有什麼好處
The first is when it is used for imaging
第一個就是它拿來做成像的時候
it has one of the biggest benefits
它有一個最大的好處
That is, the range of things that can be seen is very large.
就是它的這個可以看的東西的範圍很大
You see we can get from animals
你看我們可以從動物
that of course you all know
就是你們大家當然都知道
man is an animal
人就是個動物
So there is no problem for you to take X-ray photos
所以你X-ray去照沒有問題
That family has this X-ray that can take pictures
那人家有這個X-ray可以照碼的
according to this elephant
照這個大象的
and then there is
然後還有
can take more
可以照更多
The most important benefit is its high penetration
那最重要的好处就是它的高穿透力
I'll start over later
那我等一下会从头再讲
Another benefit is that its wavelength
那另外一个好处是它的波长
For example, when we use an Astron
譬如我们在使用的时候都是一个Astron
It's one tenth of a rice
就是零点一个耐米
or shorter at this wavelength
或者更短的这个波长
So the advantage of its short wavelength
所以它的波长很短的好处
It's kind of like when it's going this way
就是它这个行进的时候有点就像是
straight line particles
直线的粒子
it doesn't have much volatility
它没有太多的波动特性
At this time, it is your wave
那这个时候就是说你的波
when your waves are so short
你波这么短的时候
when you want to make it like
你要把它做成像的时候
For example, I make an optical microscope
譬如说我做一个光学的显微镜
I want to make a Lens
我要做一个Lens
It's usually if you guys remember this high school physics
它通常你们如果是这个高中物理还记得话
How is its resolution defined?
它的解析度怎么定义
Its resolution depends on your wavelength
它解析度是看跟你的波长有关系
So something as simple as
所以像很简单
You're like this one in the semiconductor field
你就像这个在半导体场
we felt a few years ago
我们几年前觉得
Aya they make this device
阿雅他们做这个device
Make it 0.25 micron and it will be the end
做到零点二五micron就到底啦
because they're doing it with visible light
因为他们在用可见光去做
Do Ligography
做Ligography
do this lithography
做这个光刻
then your light is
那你的光就是
is 500nm
是500nm
you have to do what you say
你要說做到
How do you make this smaller? It's about half
這個更小你怎麼做到大概一半
Its wavelength is the end
它的這個波長就到底啦
Then we think they can't do this anymore
那我們想這個他們再做不下去
But A anyway they invented a lot of weird ways
但是A反正他們發明很多奇奇怪怪的方式
A just keep going
A一直就往前走
Since then, people have been talking about
那個時候開始就有人在講說
We should do this moment with S light
我們應該用S光來做這個時刻
this lithography
這個光刻
Because the wavelength of S light is so short
因為S光的波長這麼短
away from it this
離它這個
will be limited by its wavelength
會被它波長限制的
Our name is Defreshing Limit
我們叫Defreshing Limit
far away
離得還遠得很
Well, this is of course another benefit for us.
那這個當然是我們另外好處
That is to say, we dont care about doing X-ray today
就是說我們今天我們不管做X-ray
What kind of Resolution
什麼樣的Resolution
far from this
離這個都遠得很
So we are not limited by this physical basis
所以我們不會被這個物理的基礎的這個限制
limited to
限制到
Then another X-ray
然後另外X光
Except when first invented
除了一開始發明的時候
It is not used to make images
是拿來做影像以外
soon everyone will find out
很快大家就發覺
Although it is what I just said
它雖然是我剛剛講的
Although it has few fluctuating properties
它雖然波動的特性很少
in imaging it looks like
在成像的看起來
But actually it still has
但是實際上它還是有
it's still a wave
它還是一個波
Then you can have backshot and can eat
然後你可以有倒射也可以有擅吃
These are all available
這些都是可以拿來用
It is X-ray deflection
就是X-ray deflection
It is the diffraction of X1
就是X1的繞射
a person who makes materials
是材料做材料的人
almost everyone
幾乎是每一個人
like our vice president
就像我們副院長
He's an expert at doing this X-ray scattering
他就是做這個X-ray scattering的專家
He did it from a very young age
他從很年輕的時候就做了
That fan shot too
那扇射也是
In fact, it is the same X-ray physics
其實是同樣的這個X-ray physics
That part is actually
那這個部分其實
Materials Science is also provided
提供了材料科學也好
Physics is also good
物理也好
a very large
一個非常大的
This is a very useful tool
這個非常有用的一個工具
that recently someone was saying
那最近有人在說
We actually diffract
我們其實繞射
Let's say I have a crystal
我們譬如說我有一個晶體
I have a material
我有一個材料
i want to know what it is made of
我想知道它是什麼東西做的
the easiest way
一個最簡單的辦法
In fact, it is to do an X-ray diffraction
其實就是去做一個X-ray繞射
Then because you know
然後因為知道
you know the arrangement of its atoms
你知道它的這個原子的排列
how to line up
是怎麼排
Then what is its crystal structure
然後它晶體結構什麼樣
You can get very complete information
你可以得到很完整的資訊
But if your structure
那可是如果你這個結構
not to say that there is no periodicity
不說是沒有週期性的
For example, if you don't tie the crystal award
比如說不繫上晶體獎
just me
就是我一個
A single molecule or a bunch is this
單獨一個molecule或一堆是這個
called morphous
叫morphous的
just out of order
就是沒有序的
Then you will be in X-ray like this
那你這樣在X-ray就
Because X-ray is relying on it
因為X-ray是靠著它
After each thing is arranged periodically
每一個東西它周期排列以後
it produces this constructive interference
它產生這個建設性幹涉
You will only be able to detect it later
以後造成你才可以detect到
you know when it comes out
你知道那個時候它出來
Scattering is sure to scatter
散射是一定會散射
just be with me light hits anything and it scatter
就跟我一個光照到任何東西它會散射
But it won't have a strong
但是它不會有一個很強的
this reflected this
這個反射的這個
Or let you detect
或者是讓你可以detect
So someone recently said
所以那有人就最近說
In fact, if my diffraction is strong enough
其實繞射如果我的強度夠
I can still do it like
我還是可以把它來做成像
Because no matter what
因為不管什麼東西造上
scattered things
散射的東西
I can reassemble it back to its original essence
我可以把它重組出它原來的原質
I'll wait a while for this
那這個我等一下有時間
i might talk
我可能會講一下
but this is a bit
但是這個就有點
Because it's still a long way from being an actual hero
因為現在離實際的英雄還比較遠
And then of course it's X-ray it has to do
然後它當然X-ray它有可以做
For example, your X-ray
譬如說你X-ray
You can also do energy spectrum analysis on this X-ray
這個X-光你也可以做能譜的分析
For example, the absorption of X-rays
譬如說X-光的吸收
It is directly related to each material
是跟每一個材料是有直接相關的
each element
每一個元素
its absorbing properties
它的這個吸收的這個特性
are not the same
都不太一樣
It follows your atomic number
它是跟著你的這個原子序
then when you absorb
然後你吸收的時候
The chemical state of each element
這個每一個元素它的這個化學狀態
it's the state of this chemical piece
它的這個化學件的狀態
Differently, its absorption will also
不一樣它的吸收也會
The absorption of wind will also change slightly
吸收風也會稍微有變
So you do it this absorption supplement
所以你就做它這個吸收補
or launch supplement
或者是發射補
You can get a lot of this material about it
就可以得到很多關於它這個材料
Or this analysis of this chemical state
或者是這個這個化學狀態的這個分析
Then we actually put it behind this time.
那我們這次其實放在後面
Not that it's as important as this thing
並不是說它跟這個東西一樣重要
It's rather new
而是說這個是比較新的
Then it now means that in addition to the previous
那它現在就是說除了以前
The absorbable imaging we just talked about
我們剛剛講的可以吸收的這個成像
Now there is one more new imaging mechanism for this
現在有一個多的新的成像這個機制
I'll take a moment to introduce this then wait a minute
那我會花一點時間介紹這個等一下
Of course X-ray is of course
那當然X-ray當然是
I think that's when X-ray was discovered in the first place
我想就是X-ray從一開始發現的時候
Just now the vice president was still talking about
剛剛這個副院長還在講說
he watched some old this
他看了一些老的這個
example
例子
That's when X-rays were first discovered
就是當初發現X光的時候
everyone is crazy
大家就跟瘋了一樣
And then it's basically like having this vending machine
然後基本上就像有一個這個販賣機
you can drop a dollar
你可以丟一塊錢
It will make an S-Fone for you
它就給你做一個S-Fone
You can see something like this when Google in 2010
你可以看到像这个是Google在2010年的时候
That time was 115 years
那个时候是115年
Commemoration of Mun Kwon's discovery of X-rays
文权发现X光的纪念
The earliest this is the first X-ray image
最早期这个是第一个X光的影像
This image is said to be his wife's hand
这个影像是听说是他太太的这个手
So I say he was pretty smart back then
所以我说他那个时候还蛮聪明的
I probably know what I'm doing
大概就知道自己的表现
It's his wife
其实是他太太
OK
OK
so
所以
so from then on
所以从那个时候开始
The biggest advantage of X is why he is called X
X最大的好处就是为什么他叫X
is that he is a mystery
就是他是一个迷steria
he is a very mysterious
他是一个很神秘的
He shows you things you couldn't see before
他给你看到你以前看不到的东西
like me
像我这个
I mean, I'm going to watch a movie on the plane
就是我要在飞机上看了一个电影
I think this is exactly what we're doing
我觉得这个是 exactly 我们在做的
That is to say, this is in this movie
就是说这个是这个电影里面
He said this is the one from the life magazine
他说这个是当初这个life杂志的这个
same name
作用名一样
To him is to see behind the walls
对他就是to see behind the walls
It is exactly what we X can do
就是 exactly 正好就是我们X也可以做的
How about seeing from behind the wall you can see
怎么样从看到 behind the wall 你可以看到
Like this is the X-ray image
像這個就是X-ray的影像
They scan the whole container
他們拿來scan整個貨櫃
You can actually see X-ray
你看 X-ray其實可以看得到
So of course you can see behind this wall
所以當然是可以看到這個牆後面
Look at this is also the most brief
看這個也是最簡介
like this you can see he can scan the whole
像這個你可以看到他可以scan整個
Connected to the engine of his car
連上他的車子連的引擎
can see clearly
都可以看得很清楚
Let's say this is an example
譬如說這個是一個例子
They saw a container inside
他們看到一個貨櫃裡面
There are dozens of hundreds of illegal immigrants
有幾十個上百個非法移民
One more border from Mexico to the United States
再要經過一個墨西哥到美國的邊界
So this device of the Agrin sun
所以這個Agrin太陽的裝置
The way he scans is actually like this
他scan的方式其實就是這樣
He said one is fixed
他就說一個就是固定的
a big block
一個大的擋住了
In addition, he is still active
另外他現在還有活動
like this, for example, this machine
像這個譬如說這個機器
He put it on this truck
他把放在這個卡車上
He can go to the container terminal
他可以去在貨櫃集散場
they all sweep it over
他們一個都把它掃過去
He knew what was in there
他就知道裡面放了什麼東西
like this is actually a good
像這個其實是一個很好的
This technology transfer
科技技轉的這個
This topic is all the big scanners in the mainland
這個題目是大陸所有的這種大 scanner
They are all calculated by Tsinghua University in Beijing.
都是北京清華做的計算出來
So Beijing Tsinghua University relies on this year alone
所以北京清華光靠這個一年
I heard that there can be four to five billion RAM
聽說可以有四五億的 RAM
Means this Bloyote is back
就是說這個Bloyote回來
That's generally speaking
那對一般來講
I said you can see
我就說你可以看到
That's why we love X-ray
就是說為什麼我們喜歡 X-ray
Just say you see this is not our own invention
就說你看這個不是我們自己發明
It was in the United States
就是在美國當初
I can sell you a pair of glasses
我可以給你一個賣一個眼鏡
It can be like having an X-ray edition
就可以像是有 X-ray edition
Everyone, look how happy he is
大家你看像他這樣多高興
and a dollar
而且一塊美金
OK
OK
of course it's fake
這當然是假的
But that means you can know that everyone is right
不過就是說你可以知道大家對
this period in childhood
這個時期在小時候
We've always wanted superhuman strength
我們一直希望有超人般的實力
you can see through this wall
你可以看穿透這個牆
This is X-ray
這個是 X-ray
One of the most interesting things
最令大家有興趣的一件事
like this
比如像這個
This is what I found on Google
這個都是Google上面找下來的這些
funny cartoon
好玩的卡通
Then for example like this
然後比如像這個
Also we can see all the things
也是我們可以看到所有的東西
OK, this is actually made by the same company
OK,這也是其實是同樣一個公司做的
And just talking to the vice president
而且就是跟剛剛這個副院長講
Everyone uses it for everything
大家什麼事都把它拿來用
Back then someone was shooting X-ray movies
那時候早就有人在拍X-ray movie
Not an X-ray movie
不是X-ray的 movie
It's an X-ray movie, that means everyone go
是X-ray movie,就是說大家去
just watch it move
就看著它動來動去
Then you can watch them with X-ray
那你可以看著它們有用X-ray
Let's see if your shoes fit
來看你的鞋子合不合腳
I hope it still has this foot after two years
我希望它這個腳兩年以後還在
Then there are, for example
然後還有譬如說
I don't know if you have this
這個我不知道你們有沒有
download the app for this phone
download這個手機的應用程式
Just say that after you take a photo
就說你照上去以後
after photo
照上去以後
you look like
你看起來就是像
although it's fake
雖然它是假的
it's not real
它並不是真的
then like these
然後像這些
Of course there are serious applications
那當然有比較serious的應用
Like say this is
就像譬如說這個是
X-ray is a very important application
X-ray一個很重大的應用
I mean I want to see these
就是說我希望去看這些
Whether my semiconductor manufacturing process is wind
我半導體製程不管是風裝
After these are done
這些因為做好了以後
don't need to open
不需要打開來
so at this time
所以這時候
this is what we did
這是我們自己做的
because we are limited by our
因為我們受限於我們的
This is what we call Fuel of View
就是這個我們叫Fuel of View
First we are the size of the window
首先我們是視窗的大小
So we for example say
所以我們對於一個譬如說
This SD memory card we have to take photos all the time
這SD的記憶卡我們要一直照
I've been putting it together like this
一直照這樣子把它圖拼起來
It's a bit like doing jigsaw puzzles on your mobile phone now
有點像現在你們手機在做拼圖這樣
come out and you can see
那出來你可以看到
How is there a line connected here?
這裡面有個線是怎麼接的
So let's say it's not connected well somewhere
所以說假設它裡面什麼地方接的不好
In fact, it is easy to check out with this S light.
其實用這個S光是很容易檢查出來
So most of the packaging
所以大部分在做封裝的
is the PCB
就是PCB
This is the motherboard company
就是這個主機板這些公司
In fact, we have always had many companies
其實我們一直有很多公司
Wish we did this job for them
希望我們替他們做這樣的工作
But even if these companies
但是就算這些公司
He won't give you too much money
他也不會給你太多的錢
then ask you to do many things
然後叫你做很多的事
actually those things
其實那些事
They can buy this machine by themselves
他們自己去買這個機器就可以做了
So we're mostly working on that as well
所以我們大部分也在做這方面的工作
That S light has one
那S光有一個
There should be a lot of people doing it in the yard
院裡面應該有很多人在做的
By absorbing this S-Quam from outer space this universe
用吸收這個從外太空這個宇宙來的這個S-Quam
Look at it at the time of the big bang
看看它當初這個大爆炸的時候的這個
Up to now, these astronomical problems
到現在的這些天文上面的問題
Then why did I bring this up
那這個為什麼我提出來
That is to say, this detector
就是說這個的detector
You want to detect X-ray and what we are doing X-ray is X-ray
你要detect X-ray跟我們在做的 X-ray就是 X-ray
we need to detect it
我們要detect它
It is very important to develop this detector in the middle
中間的這個發展這個detector是很重要的
Many of them come from here
那很多都是從這邊來的
That has so many benefits but also many problems
那有這麼多好處但是也有很多的問題
For example like
譬如說像
Tell him this is the truth that I have been talking about
跟他一說這個是我一直講說這個truth
sometimes is ugly
sometimes is ugly
It's just that the real world may not be as good as you think
就是這個真實的世界可能不是像你想的那麼好
but you can see through when
但你可以看穿透的時候
Then
然後
But the biggest problem is actually this
可是最大的問題其實是這個
OK so you can look at this
OK 所以你可以看看這個
Yeah I don't know you know what he's talking about
對啊 我不知道你們知道他在講什麼
OK so why is this bad
OK 那為什麼這個不好
because I just told you
就是因為我剛跟大家講了
You still have the consideration of skin color
你還是有膚色的這個考量
Yeah, I remember we were a while ago
對 那我記得我們前一陣子
That is to say, at that time, I went with this professor Zhang Weihao
就是說那個時候跟這個張維浩教授去
While in the US we visited a
美國的時候我們訪問了一個
Fellow of the American Academy of Sciences
美國科學院院士
He said he would not go abroad
他就說他不要出國
He said because he didn't want to be Scanned
他說因為他不要去被Scan
He said this Scan
他說這個Scan
He said according to his calculations
他說據他的計算
That is to say, there are thirty, twenty, forty in California
就是說像加州三二四十個
He did that Scan once
他做一次那個Scan
words like this
像這樣子的話
he did the math
他算了一下
He thinks his Dose
他覺得他那個Dose
Do half CT with you
跟你做半次CT
Half tomography is the same
半次斷層掃描是一樣的
yes ok
對啊 OK
So like this is what they put on
所以像這個就是他們當初裝的
You people go this way, go over there and raise your hands high
你人走這邊走過去手舉高
you can get
你就可以得到
And in this way they use the backlight
而且他這個方式他們就用背向光
He didn't show you the bones
他不是給你看骨頭
Because it's useless for him to look at your bones
因為他看你的骨頭沒有用
He actually wants Scan to hit you
他其實就是要Scan打到你身上以後
will reflect
會反射
Those of us who studied Scan physics at that time
那我們那時候學Scan物理的人
just feel weird
就覺得很奇怪
why such a good idea
為什麼這麼好的idea
we didn't think
我們當初沒有想到
This is all understanding
這個都是理解
A business of several billion dollars
幾個billion dollar的business
The reason is that his radiation dose is still very high
原因就是其實他的輻射的劑量還是很高
only when they are for national security
只是他們為了國家安全的時候
didn't take it as a strict script
沒有把它當作很嚴格的劇本
So Europe bans this
所以歐洲就把這個禁掉
European airports do not have such scanners
歐洲的機場就沒有這樣的scanner
In the United States, they are now also changing
美國他們現在也改
Basically they end up with
基本上他們最後還是
And like the American Academy of Sciences, they also wrote a letter to Obama
而且像美國科學院是他們還寫的信給歐巴馬
say you are for national security
說你為了國家安全
you skip these things
你把這些事都跳步了
That is to say, if you really want to make a medical device
就是說你要是真的要做一個醫療器材的話
You just review these experiments
你光是這個審核這些試驗
just to give you this license
光是給你這個證照
it could be years
就可能要好多年
But under the big hat of national security
但是為了國家安全這個大帽子之下
get it out
趕快弄出來
Then the company tells you about safety
然後公司跟你講安全
just say safe
你就說安全
Then go in and do it
然後進去就做了
so this is me in
所以這個是我在
this is where you can see us
這就是你可以看到我們
often pass like this
經常會經過像這樣
It's actually like him here
這裡面其實就是像他這樣子
X-ray
X-ray
I just told you why it's not good
剛才講說為什麼不好
you know this is a photo from long ago
你知道這就是很早的以前的一個照片
You can see him spawning XA here
你可以看到他XA在這邊產生
He's just over there looking happy
他就在那邊看得很高興
Yeah, I just said I hope they live less
對啊 我就說我希望他們能夠活得差一點
That's a wrong example
那這個是錯誤的示範
OK so now everyone
OK 所以現在大家
Decades later, everyone found out that it is very simple
幾十年以後大家發覺很簡單
Many people die very early
很多人都很早就死了
like this madame curie
像這個居里夫人
he is what he did
他就是他做的
He didn't think of this thing at that time
他那個時候他也沒有想到這個東西
but later
但是到後來
He started to get affected by the overhead beam
他就開始有受到過頭方射線的影響
like this too
像這個也是一樣
Then I'll show some more
那我再秀幾個
It's the photo of this famous person's Ace Light
就是這個比較有名的人的Ace光的照片
This was caught on the Internet
這個是網路上抓到
This is the president of the old Ross House in 1900
這個是老羅士府1900幾年的時候的總統
He got a gunshot wound on him and hit a guy
他身上他那時候被槍傷打了一個人
I heard he was beaten
聽說他被打了以後
Just like our President Chen Zhiyuan
就跟我們陳志遠總統一樣
After playing, he also gave a 90-minute TOP
打了以後他還給了一個90分鐘的TOP
no feeling at all
完全沒有感覺
only found out at the end
到最後才發覺
OK, come here, there's already a
OK,來這邊,已經有一個
There is another famous person, I think I should know about it after watching American cartoons
那另外又有有名的人,我想大概看美國卡通了應該知道
no, you can see him
沒有,可以看他這個
And when I take it, you can see that X-ray has been used for organization
而且我拿來的時候,你可以看到X-ray一直拿來做就是做組織
We can look at his physical appearance, for example, I can see that his brain is very small
我們可以看他的型貌,比如說我可以看到他的腦很小
but i don't know what he's doing
但是我不知道他在幹什麼
So I don't want to say now, we can know what is in his mind, if we can know what he is thinking
所以我不現在就說,他腦子裡面我們可以,如果可以知道他在想什麼
Then you can achieve the effect of the function, the function image
那你就可以達到功能的這個效果,功能影像
OK, there is another very famous X-ray, I dont know if you can recognize it
OK,另外還有一個很有名的這個X-ray,我不知道你們可不可以認得出來
Called Tony Stark
叫Tony Stark
Then you can see that after he came out, his measurements reconstructed it
然後你可以看他這個出來以後,他的三圍把它重建起來
You can look like this, this person I think you should probably know him
你可以看像這個樣子,這個人我想你們大概應該知道就是他
OK, this is that one, and there is a famous X-ray
OK,這是那個,那還有一個很有名的這個X-ray的
Then this is Franklin
那這個是Franklin
This is the first X-ray image of DNA
這是第一個DNA的X-ray的影像
I think the deputy dean should be very clear
我想這個副院長應該就很清楚
Everyone thought he should have won the Nobel Prize
他本來大家都認為他應該拿諾貝爾獎的
As a result, Jin Watson and Luke Tan took his picture away
結果被金瓦森跟盧克坦把他這個圖就拿走了
I wrote the result but didn't include it
寫了結果也沒有把它放進來
This is a very famous X-ray
這個是非常有名的一個X-ray的
but not like this
但是不是成這樣
Choose to wrap
選擇繞設
X-ray was used and many other tasks were done
X-ray拿來還做了很多其他的工作
like this is a i don't know what this is
像是這是一個我不知道這是什麼
But it's also famous
但是這也是很有名的話
After you read it with X-ray
你用X-ray看了以後
They can see that actually inside
他們可以看到說其實裡面
Because if there is, you could have written it first
因為有的話你本來就可以裡面先寫一次
Then you can change
然後你可以改
So they can see in this way that he is actually another painting inside
所以他們用這個方式可以看到他其實裡面本來是另外一幅畫
they later changed it all
他們後來把它全部改掉
Then there is another famous
然後還有一個蠻有名的
This is the mummy found in Egypt
這是在埃及找到的木乃伊
This is what a cat looks like
這是貓的外型
But it actually has a hair wrapped in it
但是它裡面其實真的是有一隻毛包在裡面
this is his body
這是他的屍體
So these x-rays
所以這些的X光
When in use are standing in a shit
在使用的時候都是站在一個屎
that I can penetrate
就是我可以穿透
I can also see inside
我也可以看到裡面
Can satisfy everyone's good habits
可以滿足大家的好習性
So how can I open this thing
所以我這個東西我怎麼樣能夠打開
For example, people are a very troublesome thing
比如說人是一個很麻煩的事
people
人
I remember one time the Discovery Channel was saying
我記得 Discovery Channel 有一次在講說
19th century
19世紀
The greatest and most important medical method is the inner century
最偉大最重要的醫學方法是內世紀
This is the first time someone stuffed a mirror into your belly
第一次人家把一個鏡子塞到你的肚子裡面去
can see inside
可以看到裡面
It's very Fascinating
這是很Fascinating
Trouble with people because of animals or people
因為人的動物或者人的麻煩
For example, if you want to see inside
比如說你要看到裡面
unless you kill it
你除非把它殺掉
Now finally there is a thing that is
現在好不容易有一個東西是
i can watch while i'm alive
我可以在活的時候看
popular at the time
當時大家用的流行
You can see this is also an old ad
你可以看到這也是一個老的廣告
You can see them claiming to say
你可以看到他們在號稱說
After taking a double photo, you won't have a headache
A雙照照以後你頭就不痛
i think it might be
我想可能是
You see this nerve has been injured
你看這個神經都已經受傷了
But it's not impossible
但是這個並不是一個不可能的事
you can watch this now
你可以看現在這個
For example, our friend is in the mountains
比如說我們朋友在山中
he gave me this
他給我這個
This is an active accelerator
這是一個現行的加速器
It can produce fine X-rays like this coin
它可以產生就像這樣子很細的X光的這個幣
it's doing radiation therapy
它在做放射性治療
Usually during radiotherapy
一般在做放射性治療的時候
I'll just say I know there's a tumor here
我就說我知道這邊有腫瘤
I will follow
我去照著
But when I take pictures, I don't want to take pictures of them all
但是我照的時候我不要全部都照
nowhere else
別的地方不需要
will make a cover
就會做一個罩子
put this place
把這個地方
X-rays in other places are blocked
其他的地方X光擋下來
I made a little progress later
後來做的進步一點
I just don't want to do it once
就是我不要一次做
do it here
這邊做
Because X-rays don't tell the difference
因為X光它不分這個青紅皂白
all injured
全部都打傷了
I'll do a few more angles
我就多做幾個角度
I can do 10 angles
我可以做10個角度
Like it claims to be able to do these 1000 angles
像它這個號稱是可以做這1000個角度
I know where your tumor is
就是我知道你的腫瘤在哪裡
I move this coin
我動這個幣
i've been following it
我一直照著它走
The advantage is that when I was in cancer
好處就是說我在腫瘤的時候
I can give it, for example, its dose of 1
我可以給它譬如它的這個劑量是1
elsewhere it's
其他的地方它就
actually only one thousandth
實際上只有一千分之一
If it uses a thousand of this projection
如果它用一千個這個projection
will effectively reduce the
就會很有效的降低這個
Radiation therapy to normal tissue
放射性治療對正常組織
So how could it work
所以它有什麼可能效
but this is of course not
但是這個當然不是
Image application
影像的應用
But you also know like him
不過你也知道像他這裡面
The most important part of this technology
這個科技最重要的地方
In fact, its not that I made this detector to do this.
其實並不是說我把這個detector做來做這個事
another you locate
另外一個你定位
Like for example he does a lot of these two treatments
像譬如說他做很多這兩個治療
For example, you may be able to receive
比如說你受到可能還可以
because you are fixed
因為你是固定的
You have a small tumor on your body
你身上你做一個很小的腫瘤
or a tumor of, say, a centimeter or two
或者是一個比如說一兩公分的腫瘤
The person on you is moving and breathing
你身上的人在動在呼吸
So they have to have good video equipment nearby
所以他們附近都要有很好的影像設備
Usually when you go to a hospital there are two big x-ray machines
通常你去像在醫院會有兩個大X光機放在那裡
Then under him is his detector
然後他底下是他的detector
he can at the same time
他在能夠同時
Track your body's movements
追蹤你的身體的運動
Then when he set
然後他在設的時候
he predictably said
他可以預測說
I'm now you're selling me like this
我現在你現在在賣我在這樣
or you breathe
或者是你呼吸
he next time
他在下一個時間
Where will you move when he moves to this point?
他當動到這個時候你會動到哪裡
You are still making predictions
你還用在做預測
Speaking of this focus
講到這個聚焦
we mean
我們就是說
when doing imaging
在做成像的時候
For example, usually you do it in a hospital
比如說一般的你在醫院做
I'll talk about why the hospital can't do it later
我等一下會講說醫院的為什麼做不到
made these more detailed videos
做的這些比較精細的影片
that image
那個影像
that reason is that
那個原因就是那個
This quality of iShade
iShade的這個品質
Its light source is of poor quality
它的光源的品質太差
That also has a better iShade light source
那也有好一點的iShade的光源
I use a very small
就是我用很小的
I let it focus called very small
我讓它聚焦叫很小
It produces a small spot of light
它產生光點就很小
then we bring it
那我們把它拿來
for example look at this
比如說看看這個
This IC
這個IC啊
Check out this Madeleboa these
看看這個Madeleboa這些
we actually
我們就其實
this is for
這個是用
It can be done without synchronous auxiliary test
不需要用同步輔測就可以做的
can do it now
現在就可以做
then use this way
那用這個方式
i'm talking about this
我在講我這個
Before using the synchronous test
用同步輔測的之前
I will talk about this project
我會講一個這個project
This has nothing to do with audiovisual
這個跟聲音影像沒有什麼關係
but what we recently did
但是我們最近做的
because it's interesting
因為還蠻有意思
And I think this will be of interest to everyone
而且我想這個大家會有興趣的
that is to say this
就是說這個
This is our latest
這個是我們最近
with our European
在跟我們這個歐洲的
this collaborator
這個合作的人
they are saying they are
他們是說他們在
this place is in venice
這個地方是在威尼斯
Venice means they are a port
威尼斯就是說他們這是一個港口
from hundreds of years
從幾百年來
access to all their ports
他們所有港口的進出
must have many files
都要有很多檔案
then this file
那這個檔案
He could count millions, numbers like this
他算起來可能有百萬 像這樣子的數
In a room like this, there might be thirty rooms like this
放在像這樣子的房間 這樣子的房間可能有三十間
So something like this would say
所以這樣子的東西就是說
In fact, because he is not like the dead sea scripture
其實因為他又不是像那個死海經文
You just take one roll and I'll find a way to finish it
你就一捲 我就想辦法把它弄完
He has a lot so you don't want
他這有很多 所以你又不希望
It's not just about him being afraid of his damage
就不光是說他怕他damage的問題
For example, you've been through something like this
比如說你過過模樣的東西來
Of course you don't want you to drive around
你當然不希望你開來開去
So of course there will be injuries when this is opened.
所以這個當然打開來一定會有受傷
But the most important reason is not this
但是這最重要的原因不是這個
Instead we want to be able to quickly put it into arcibe
而是我們希望能夠快速的把它arcibe
It's a bit like a digital power plant in our courtyard
有點像我們院裡面在做數位電廠一樣
they just thought
他們就是說想到
The people we worked with thought of doing it with X-rays
我們合作的人他們想到說用X光來做
what is he going to do
他要怎麼做呢
He told me not to open the book
他就說我書不要打開
I lock up I do tomography
我關起來 我做tomography
I do tomography
我做斷層掃描
I can finally put the contents inside
我最後可以把裡面的東西
It is the way of reading without opening the book
就是不開書的開書閱讀方式
You can grab all the text inside
你可以把裡面的text全部抓出來
Well, we've just started doing a little
那我們剛剛開始在做一點
This is actually pretty exciting
這個其實還蠻興奮的
Because now Venice has a very famous society
因為現在威尼斯他有一個很有名的society
In vain
Vanis
When they invited us to do it in June
他們邀請我們在六月做的時候
They will go to a Public Event
他們會去給一個Public的Event
Tell everyone that they are ready to officially start
告訴大家說他們準備正式開始進行
Later on their side
以後他們這邊
if done well
如果做得好的話
they will buy dozens
他們會買幾十台
The S2 machine like this
這樣子的S2機
put it on over there
在那邊裝上去
Scan it down for each one
每一個就把它scan下來
We did some Pre-Limit results
我們做了一些Pre-Limit的結果
I just want to say that this is a Mass manuscript I bought.
就想說這個是買的一個Mass manuscript
actually it's interesting
其實這很有意思
that means i'm thinking right away
就是說我馬上就想
Why can't it be done in our hospital?
為什麼不能拿到我們院裡面做
Or the Palace Museum
或者是這個故宮博物院
the place of difference
那個差異之所
this europe from
這個歐洲從
Beginning less than a thousand years AD
西元不到一千年開始
while they were writing
他們在書寫的時候
From the one called InkGull
從那個叫做InkGull
it this is a number
它這個是一個數字
count three removed things
數三個取下的東西
a bit like jelly sauce
一個有點像膠醬
The compounded thing is this iron oxide particle
配合的東西是這個氧化鐵的顆粒
So it has metal content in it
所以它裡面是有金屬含量的
So X-ray can be seen
所以X-ray是可以看得到
The east is more advanced
那東方的是比較進步的
Dongfang uses the Song Ni box is the carbon in the X-ray
東方用松霓箱是碳在X光裡面
there is no comparison
就沒有對比
So the way Europe looks like this
所以歐洲這個樣子的方式
It took almost a thousand years to a few years in the 1880s
它用了快一千年到一八幾幾年的時候
to the nineteenth century
到十九世紀的時候
They only accepted the ink from the East after it came in
他們才接受了東方的這個墨汁進來以後
They just started using this
他們才開始用這個
So the benefit is to become
所以這個好處就是變成
We have so many hundreds of years of Windows
我們有這麼幾百年的Windows
You can do it with SWIT
用SWIT都可以做
Then we tried it and it turned out to be like this example
那我們試了一下果然像這個例子
This one is from 1566 and it's written on it
這個的是1566年的一個上面寫的
this is its age
這就是它的年代
This Manual Script was first written in 1566
1566年的一個首寫的這個Manual Script
Then ours is visible light
那我們這個是可見光的
We will do S light now
我們現在就做了S光以後
we stack it
我們把它疊起來
you can watch slowly
你可以看慢慢的
This is our S light video
這個就是我們的S光的影片
This Manual Script
這個Manual Script
Unfortunately is very unfortunate
Unfortunately就是很不幸的
mean it's inside
是說它裡面
we are talking
我們在說
Our students are talking about our Posa
我們那些學生在講我們的Posa
Said it was black heart ink
說這是它買到黑心墨水
Actually there's nothing in it
其實裡面沒有什麼
what's this like
這有什麼樣
so you can see
所以你可以看到
Our paper sees clearly
我們的紙看得很清楚
but the paper can't see
但是紙看不見
like this, good, like this
像這個的話,就很好,像這個
You can see it, we're like stacking it directly on top of it
你可以看到它,我們像直接把它疊上去
You can see that the back is now S1 looking at this in the past
你可以看到後面現在就是S1看過去的這個
This is the image made by S1
這個是S1做出來的這個影像
So it means that at least this word can be developed
所以表示說最起碼這個字是可以顯影
So it's important for me to come back and talk to people about developer
所以我這樣回來去跟人講說顯影劑是很重要的
You dont have a developer for this thing, no matter how good your image is in terms of resolution
你這個東西沒有顯影劑,你的影像不管是解析度再好
No matter how fast you are, it's useless
你的這個速度再快都沒有用
So what becomes of this manipulating this developer
所以變成怎麼樣這個操控這個顯影劑
It becomes a great knowledge, so generally this
就變成一個很大的學問,所以一般的這個
The medical imaging equipment, in the developer market
這個醫療影像的設備,在顯影劑的這個市場
Usually it accounts for one-third to one-half of its market
通常就要佔到三分之一到二分之一它的這個市場
Then we made a very simple simulation, because we can't afford it yet
那我們做了一個很簡單的模擬,因為我們現在還買不起
Or you can't get the book, because we got a
或者拿不到它那個書,就是我們弄了個
industrial stack it on top of each other and do the rotation
實業把它疊在一起,然後做旋轉
Then let's try to solve this by hand
那我們現在試著把這個比手把它解出來
After they are solved, they can be identified
解出來以後就可以,它們再去辨識
Then use this small X-ray code
那同樣用這種小的這個X光碼
It is our laboratory that can buy it
就是我們這個實驗室就可以買得到
It won't be very expensive to install
裝起來也不會很貴的
we can already do it
我們已經可以做到
For example, look at the cerebral blood vessels of this mouse
譬如說像看這個小鼠的腦血管的這個
it's the whole brain the whole brain
這是整個的腦 全腦
so you can see
所以你可以看到
When there are not many diseases that can be identified here
當這裡面可以分辨的病不多
didn't get what we wanted
沒有到我們想要的
but this is because
但是這是因為
In this brain of your mouse
你的小鼠這個腦裡面
let it hit this developer
讓它打這個顯影劑
The same problem with developer
一樣是處理顯影劑的這個問題
That's not because of insufficient resolution
那並不是因為解析度不夠
can look like this
可以看像這樣子
You can see that we just made a few angles
你可以看我們就說做了幾個角度
You can see how the distribution of its blood vessels looks like
你可以看到它這個血管的分布的樣子
OK, so what I want to tell you now is that
OK 那我現在要跟大家講的就是說
X-rays of these
這些的X-ray
That is to say, no more than
就是說沒有超過
Most of us can now do
我們現在大部分的人可以做
But what I'm going to tell you now
但是我現在要跟大家講的
That is to say, I actually said
就是說我其實本來就說
Is this this X-ray from your grandfather's time
這是不是你祖父時代的這個X-ray
That means we can be safe with this
這就是說這個我們可以很安全
ask any of this doctors
去問任何的這個醫生
you talk to him
你跟他講說
This X-ray can be compared
這個X-ray可以做相對比
he has absolutely no idea what you're talking about
他絕對不知道你在講什麼
Then you can say can do
然後你可以說可以做
Of course he doesn't know about the elements and chemical composition
做元素跟化學成分他當然也不知道
You see, it is said that 15 nanometers can be achieved
你看講說可以做到15奈米
Or at this time he won't believe it
或者是這個時候他更是不會相信
But this is all because of what Fu Yuannan said just now.
但是這都是因為得利於我剛剛這個傅遠南講的
this synchrotron radiation
這個同步輻射
S-light produced by synchrotron radiation
同步輻射他的產生的S光
His quality is very good
他的品質是非常好的
That is to say, if you want to compare synchrotron radiation
就是說同步輻射你要比起來的話
It's kind of like a laser
就有點像是雷射一樣
When imaging, especially the imaging of S light
那在成像的時候特別是S光的成像
Say you're going to do
比如說你要去做
I'll talk later
等一下我再講好了
Because this way we can do a comparison
因為這樣我們可以做相對比
There are many different ways of comparing
相對比有很多種不同的方式
But the basic principle is that
但是基本上的原理就是說
I these two materials like I would have been
我這兩個材料就像我本來是
would give an example like your glass of water
會舉個例子不像你一杯水
When you drink water you are in a bottle
你水的時候你在個瓶子裡面
If it is full, you cannot see its interface
如果是滿的時候你看不到它的界面
You don't know it's you just look at it and don't touch it
你不知道它是你光去看它不去動它
You don't know it's oil and water
你不知道它是油水沒水
but when you're half full
但是你半滿的時候
you can see that surface
你可以看到那個表面
Why
為什麼
This is actually not because of absorption.
這是其實並不是因為吸收的關係
but because of refraction
而是因為折射
Because its surface no matter what
因為它這個表面不管怎麼樣
Your visible light passes to your side
你這可見光經過到你這邊
it has some folds
它有一些折身
you can watch it edge
你可以看著它邊緣
so you can tell it's water
所以你可以判斷它是水面
But today is full
不過今天填滿了
That is to say, its absorption of light by water
就是說它水的對光的吸收
Absorption of visible light
可見光的吸收
Not much different from air
跟空氣沒有差太多
so you don't have a mechanism that can image
所以你就沒有可以成像的機制
then we are now saying
那我們現在就是說
use this word
用這個的話
That is to say, S light affects different materials
就是說S光對不同的材料
It absorbs differently
它的吸收會有不一樣
That is to say, the absorption of bone and meat is of course different.
就是說骨頭跟肉吸收當然不一樣
But S only changes bones
可是S光換骨頭
I have seen it for more than a hundred years
已經看了一百多年
then you can't watch anything else
那你不能看別的東西
because of something else
因為別的東西
Its absorption between the flesh and the flesh
它的這個吸收肉跟肉之間
Its absorption of S light
它對S光的吸收
are almost the same
都是幾乎是一樣的
then we are thinking now
那我們現在就在想
if that is to say
如果就是說
But these two organizations
但是這兩個組織
Its absorption of S light
它的這個對S光的吸收
Although it is very close
雖然是很接近
But its refractive index is not the same
但是它的這個折射率不太一樣
The refractive index of S light is not the same
對S光的折射率不太一樣
it's on the edge
那它在邊緣
will cause some refraction effect
就會造成一些折射的效果
You may have a chance to catch the edge of it
你可能就有機會抓到它的邊緣
This is the so-called copper axial contrast
這是所謂銅軸向對比
The other is to get it in a different way
那其它是用不同的方式來取得它
The refractive index of each material is different
每個材料的折射率不一樣
The so-called comparative
所謂相對比
Because when compared to the positive wave
因為相對於正值波的時候
it affects its future
它影響它的向未
The future of the wave is because of your material
波的向未是被你這個材料
that is to say like the refractive index
就是說像折射率
Is the refractive index that affects it
是影響它的refractive index
There are several different ways
這裡面有幾種不同方式
It's all on X-ray now
現在都已經在X光
These are known when visible light rises
這些都是在可見光漲就知道的
Like Zernikey, Contra, Zernikey
比如說Zernikey, Contra, Zernikey
Wait for Wire Price in the 1950s and 1960s
等Wire Price的1950幾年,1960幾年的事
Up to now, it can be done in XGrade
到現在就在XGrade裡面可以做得到
i just told you
我剛剛跟大家講的
X-rays have the ability to distinguish elements
X光對元素有區分的能力
It also has the ability to distinguish its chemical composition
對它的化學成分也有區分的能力
So we can use this way
所以我們就可以用這個方式
We look at the same iron
我們一樣看同樣一個鐵
inside the plastic
在塑膠裡面
We can know that this iron is not only
我們可以知道這個鐵不單是
And it's oxidized iron oxide
而且它是氧化的幾太的氧化鐵
is to use this imaging method
就是用這個成像的方式
I will talk about the resolution later
解析度我後面會再講
Defresher image
Defresher image
This is relative to the current development of a new exchange
這個是相對於現在有一個新的發展交
What we call X-ray finally has
我們叫做X光終於有了
This was the earliest when Ronald Reagan was president
這個最早以前在雷根做總統的時候
There is that new battle plan to do at the beginning
有那個新戰計畫當初要做的
Only hope I get a really strong S-1
只有希望我弄一個很強很強的S-1
You can just shoot the missile down
可以就直接把飛彈打下來
or take down someone else's satellite
或把別人的衛星打下來
but it never worked out
但是一直沒有成
But the concept of this is the development of this
但是這個的concept就是這個的發展
continues until now
延續到現在
Now there are real lasers
現在真的有雷射
I think we are now using an accelerator
就覺得我們現在用一個加速器的方式
Make this S-1 out
做成這個S-1出來
it's like a laser
就是像是雷射一樣
it has good coherence
它有很好的相干性
good destructive
有很好的損殖性
The application of this in the next few years
這個的應用在後面幾年
i think it will come out slowly
我想會慢慢出來
But it's just now
但是現在就還剛剛
For example, the first such machine
比如說第一個這樣子的機器
Started using it about two years ago at Stanford
在Stanford大概兩年前開始用
four years
四年
In Japan, it may have been used two years ago
日本的話可能是兩年前開始用
we now also hope
我們現在也希望
We are in Zhongyuanyuan
我們在中原院
be able to have some planning for using this aspect
能夠有一些使用這個方面的規劃
my own hope is to say
我自己的希望是說
In 2015 we were able to
我們能夠在2015年的時候
Take this S-1 resolution
把這個S-1的解析度
are pushing further from Sunaimi to this road Nanami
都在進一步從蘇奈米推到這個路奈米
Then I have some nano
那我奈米有一些
There is an important development
有一個重要的development
It's like this image reconstruction method called tomography.
就是像這個叫做斷層掃描的影像重建法
when you do a normal tomography scan
就是你在一般做斷層掃描的時候
while we are doing
我們在做的時候
For example, my image
譬如說我這一個影像
I take an angle
我取一張角度
Then I rotate this sample
然後我旋轉這個樣品
or rotate your light source
或者旋轉你的光源
I took it variously for future
我取了它各種面向以後
I reconstructed it mathematically
我用數學的方式把它重組出來
its three-dimensional entity
它三度空間的實體
It used to be said that I wanted a lot from the angle I took.
以前是說我取的這個角度我要很多
Because you take less angles
因為你取的角度少的話
you'll end up jumping
你終會就跳步一樣
You have some places you will miss like this
你有些地方你就會miss這樣
So becomes what you now assume
所以變成你現在假設
we usually do
我們通常在做
We made this image at Statistical Services
我們在統計服務的做這個影像
We may take 360 sheets
我們可能會取有360張
It means that we take, for example, a half-time
就表示我們譬如說半度取一張
Take 180 degrees
取180度
Or even you want more to get 1000
或者是甚至你要更多來取1000張
But in the past, if it was used on humans
但是以前還如果用在人身上
Now generally used
現在一般用
They all want as little as possible
他們大家都希望越少越好
The less I have this angle of this exposure
我越少的這個曝光的這個角度
I can reassemble the best
我就可以重組出最好
so i tried this
所以我想這個
A lot of people who are working on this side are doing this
很多在做這邊的人都在這方面
This is a 2012 job
這是一個2012年的工作
they think they have a new way
他們認為他們有一個新的方式
under conditions of little projection
可以在很少的投影的狀況之下
You can get a very good three-dimensional reconstruction
就可以得到很好的三維重組的
let me mention this
這個事我提一下
Because the collaborators of this group
因為這個組的合作的人
It was called a theory with our chief Li Lingguo
是跟我們的首長李令國叫做做理論的
he is also interested in this
他對這個也很有興趣
They just said they were doing some work on this
他們就說他們有在做一些這方面的工作
This is a breast tissue
這是一個乳房的組織
this place is kind of oil
這個地方是種油
He can use very little dirt
他可以用很少的髒處
Very few projections can be made
很少的projection就可以做出來
Now during mammography
現在在做乳房攝影的時候
Basically he only does one
基本上他只做一張
They now have people say do tomothin fact
他們現在有人說做tomothin事實
He might be able to do some angles
他可能可以做幾顆角度
They claim to do better
他們號稱會做得比較好一點
Alvation develop like this goes on
像這樣子的Alvation develop下去
Maybe after being so supernatural now
也許在現在這樣靈異後
It is easy to get the structure of 3-dimensional space
就可以很容易得到3度空間的結構
It is of course helpful to judge them
對他們的判斷當然是很有幫助
when i see the two now
我現在看到兩位的時候
something in the middle
中間有東西
But his relative position
但是他的相關位置
For example, these small generalization points
譬如說這些小的概化點
It correlates to the location of breast cancer judged by doctors
它相關的位置對醫生判斷的乳癌
still very helpful
還是很有幫助
Many of their doctors would like to be able to do this
他們很多醫生都希望能夠做這樣子
This is another TOMO SENSOR
這是另外一個做TOMO SENSOR
I just use a few pictures to get results like TOMOGRAPHY
我就是用幾張能夠得到像是TOMOGRAPHY的結果
Like the result of broken seedlings
像是斷成少苗的結果
In addition, some development is very important
另外有一些development很重要的
For example, the S-light detector
譬如說S-光的探測器
S-light detector when we started doing S-light
S-光探測器在我們開始做S-光的時候
We are thinking of using it on people
我們在想用到人身上
Definitely the best sensitivity
一定明感度都是最好的
But in fact, there are still technological developments
但是實際上還是有跟科技的發展
like i remember years ago
像我記得在前幾年
When everyone uses a camera, it is still a CCD
大家用照相機的時候都還是CCD
CCD is a kind of device
CCD是一種device
No one is using CCD now
現在沒有人在用CCD
Now almost all are C-MOS detectors
現在幾乎全部是C-MOS detector
The X-ray detector only has different materials in the upper part
X-ray這個探測器它只是在上面的度的材料不一樣
Mine is sensitive to S-light
我這個是對S-光感光的
but produces this
但是產生這個
The way the signal is actually very close
信号的方式其实是很接近的
that has another subscript
那有另外一个底标
This is what we have in our lock now
这个是我们现在我们的锁里面有
Come to be the chairman and academician
来做理事长院士
Then this is of course ready-made
那这个当然是现成
H&D type already available
已经可以买得到的H&D type
But this company is the Swiss Syncertron
但是这家公司是瑞士的Syncertron
It has a kid team when it's ready
它有一个小子team做好了以后
they turned it out
他们把它既转出来的
So this is a very successful example
所以这是一个很成功的例子
I was originally because the scientists wanted to use
我本来是因为科学家要用
I'm going to use this nice thing
我要用这个好的东西
After getting it done, they found it very useful
弄好以后他们发觉很好用
just went out and started a company
就出去开了一个公司
The company is quite successful now
那这个公司现在还蛮成功的
a detector like this
像这样一个detector
when he first came out
他刚出来的时候
their name is
他们的这个号称是
One pixel one dollar
一个pixel一块美金
So like this 6 million pixel
所以像这个600万pixel
it this Ding-san
它这个Ding-san
It's Bohata down to about
就是波哈他降到大概就是
Let's say $1 million
比如说100万美金
like this
像这样
Then this detector
那这个detector
He does everything
他就是每一个全部做起来
his usual place is
他的常处就是
a pixel in me
我里面一个像素
I have an electronic system
我就有一个电子系统
i've always been i've been like
我从就是我就像是
put a small detector in the
把一个小的detector放在
put it together
把它拼起来一样
Then his advantage is his predecessor
那他好处就是他的这个前级
put these things together
这些东西都放在一起
its noise will be less
它的noise就會很少
So their detector claims to say
所以他們這個detector號稱說
we put it there
我們放在那裡
like you now your CC
就像你現在你的CC
your regular camera
你的一般的照相機
mobile phone camera
手機的照相機
when it's dark
你要照很暗的時候
why not
為什麼不行
you soon it's noise
你很快它的noise
It has a lot of signal noise
它的訊號雜訊就很多
you shoot longer
你拍得久一點
Noise overwhelms your image
雜訊就蓋過你的那個影像
like it this
像它這個
you can shoot for half an hour
你可以拍半個小時
no noise
沒有雜訊
that of course
那這個當然
That is to say, it is used for medical purposes.
就是說拿來做醫學
This imaging is very good
這個成像很好啊
why no one does
為什麼沒有人做
then you will know why
那你就知道為什麼
that's too expensive
那也太貴
then we know this company
那我們知道這個家公司
Its IC is made in Taiwan
它的這個IC是在台灣做的
because the world has only
因為全世界只有
Taiwan's TSMC and UMC
台灣的TSMC跟聯電
It can accept this small
它可以接受這種小的這種
Small quantity for this order
小量的這個訂單
So their IC is made in Taiwan
所以他們的這個IC是在台灣做
so they just go out later
所以他們只是出去以後
Plus their detector
再加上他們這個detector
The class of this material
這個材料的類
That's so expensive
那這賣這麼貴
So after we made an appointment with the chairman
所以我們跟理事長約翅談了以後
he thinks this thing
他認為這個東西
Taiwan should have no problem doing
台灣應該沒有問題可以做
So we now have a program
所以我們現在有一個program
The director's office is that they made a similar detector a while ago
理事長院是他們前一陣子做了類似的detector
The detector is in front of Japan
detector前面是日本
they did deletronics
他們做了deletronics
Just cooperate with Japan's Free Latch on Laser
就跟日本的Free Latch on Laser合作
they took
他們拿去的
But after they took it, it seems that there is no afternoon
但是他們拿去以後好像沒有什麼下午
they said fine fine thank you
他們說很好很好謝謝
no more
就沒有再繼續了
It means that we are actually capable of doing this
表示說我們其實是我們是有能力在做這個事
Because they must be able to do it in Japan
因為日本他們一定是可以做
It's just that what they may do is not what we do
只是他們可能做的沒有我們這邊做的
About X-rays related to Naimi
關於X光跟耐米有關係的
I just used this example
我剛剛用這個例子
Manufacture of the first of our Nami components
第一個我們耐米元件的製造
It's the X-ray we just talked about
就是X光我們剛剛講說
We can do very high resolution
我們可以做很高的解析度
But the reason for this is why it couldn't be done before
但是這個的原因為什麼以前不能做
It's because now we have the technology made by Nami
是因為現在我們有耐米製造的技術
We can do X-ray optics
我們可以做X光的光學元件
achieve very good resolution
做到非常好的解析度
In addition, we just told you
另外我們剛跟大家講
X-ray resolution enhancement
X光你解析度提升
It's useless if you don't compare
你沒有對比也是沒有用
I'll give you a piece of meat now
我現在給你一塊肉
Your resolution is as high as possible
你的解析度高到再高
You put it under your S1 is white
你放到你的S1下面是白的
you are useless
你也沒有用
So to develop this nanoparticle
所以要發展這個奈米顆粒
The developing machine and the calibration machine are very important
這位顯影機跟標定機是非常重要
before doing this
在沒有做到這個之前
It's useless for you to increase the resolution
你提高解析度是沒有用的
Then we say in another
那我們在另外一個就是說
we actually this
我們其實這個
At the same time, make this S1
同時把這個S1做到
When you can see nanometer resolution
可以看到奈米解析度的時候
We can also do a lot about this
我們也可以做很多關於這個
Natal technology
Natal technology
For example, we can study
比如說我們可以研究說
When we are doing electroplating
我們在做電鍍的時候
why is it better
為什麼這樣做比較好
it's not good to do that
那樣做比較不好
Usually you have to cut it
平常的話你要切開來
It is very troublesome to use e-sports to watch
要去用電競去看很麻煩
we can now at
我們現在可以在
Even when I'm electroplating
即使就是我在電鍍的時候
Just look at how long it is
直接就看它怎麼長
then adjust to its best condition
然後調整到它最好的條件
so this is a feedback
所以這是一個feedback
That's when we have this nice nano
就是當我們有很好的這個奈米的
When this detection technique
這個檢測的技術的時候
It will also be helpful for our nano-manufacturing
對我們的奈米的製造也會有幫助
Then there is another one
那還有另外一個就是說
When we were doing this S1 imaging
當我們在做這個S1成像的時候
The location of your sample
你的這個樣品的定位
for example
比如說
Then I said to do this Tomography
然後我說要做這個Tomography
I'm going to do this tomography
我要做這個斷層掃碼
i let it turn
我讓它轉
There is no mechanical equipment
現在沒有任何一個機械設備
So it can be said that when I turn
所以說可以說我轉的時候
this thing
這個東西
You now have our Naimi resolution images
你現在我們的耐米解析度的影像
So the size of this whole
所以這個整個的大小
Only 10micron
才10micron
i just told you
我剛剛跟大家講
Hair is 100micron
頭髮是100micron
it's your hair
是你的頭髮
One out of ten Full of you
十分之一的一個Full of you
and now you have to turn something
然後你現在要轉一個東西
you want it this axis
你希望它這個軸
stay here
待在這裡
mechanically impossible
機械上是做不到的
so it becomes
所以就變成
you zoom it in
你把它放大來看
when you turn
你在轉的時候是這樣
This way this reorganized this
這樣子這個重組的這個
There is no way to do this calculation
這個演算方式就沒有辦法做
So we have to try our best to find a way
所以變成我們要盡量想辦法
fix this problem
改解決這個問題
One solution is to say
一個解決辦法就是說
when i let it take a step
我讓它轉一步的時候
I will tune
我就調
I need a good positioning
我要很好的定位
i know where it is
我知道它在哪裡
After turning
轉了以後
I'll let it recalibrate
我就讓它再校正回來
This is what we are currently doing
這是我們現在目前在做的
Before I talk about some practical examples
在我講一些實際的例子
Then before I would
然後之前我就要
Let me first tell you about this cooperator.
我先把這個合作的人先跟大家講一下
I put it in yellow to be a physics person
我放成黃的就是做物理人
That is to say, they make this equipment like me
就是說他們是跟我一樣做這個設備
Then do this development
然後做這個發展的
including in Switzerland, in the U.S. and in South Korea
包括在瑞士 在美國 還有在韓國
OK
OK
Then my own Team probably has so many people now
那我自己的Team現在大概是有這麼多人
Then the yellow one is the Queen of the National Society
然後黃色的是就是國社後
that's all we did
我們做了就這幾個事
You can see that the whole combination is our current Program
你可以看到整個合起來就是我們現在的Program
The biggest goal of doing this Program is
做這個Program當中最大的目標是
I hope it can give us the same radiation as Taiwan.
希望能夠給我們台灣這個同物輻射
The new accelerator
新建的這個加速器
A scientific project for this storage ring
這個儲存環的一個科學的計畫
This is what we are using now
這個是現在我們在用的
Called Taiwan Line Source
叫做台灣Line Source
This is Taiwan's Photon Source
這叫台灣的Photon Source
If you have the opportunity to visit now
那你現在如果有機會去參觀的話
This outer body is finished
這個外面的主體已經完工了
Thank you so much now
現在真的謝謝
They may be hoping within the next year
他們可能是希望明年之內
If users in Taiwan can start using it next year
如果明年可以給台灣的用戶開始使用
The XFE I was talking about just now is the free electron laser
我剛剛在講的XFE就是自由電子雷射
This is an accelerator in Japan called SprayA
這個是日本的一個加速器叫SprayA
It is the statistical radiation with the highest energy in the world
它這個是全世界當能量最高的統計輻射
And also a very good quality one
而且也是品質非常好的一個
This is their free electron laser
這是他們的自由電子雷射
This length is about 700 meters
這個長度大概700公尺
So it takes 700 meters to accelerate this electron
所以它用700公尺來加速這個電子
Also after some processing
同時經過一些處理以後
so that its final can produce very strong
讓它的最後可以產生非常強
It is a very short pulse
它一個脈衝是很短的
Say 50-50 Fantlose Second
比如說50-50個Fantlose Second
Fantlose Second is better than Pico in...
Fantlose Second就比Pico在...
OK is Nano and below is Pico
OK 是Nano下面是Pico
Pico is Fantlose again
Pico再來是Fantlose
Each is 1000 times worse
每一個都差1000倍
So it's this...
所以它的這個...
Time is it, this wave is a very short pulse
時間是它這個波是很短的一個pulse
In such a short pulse
在這麼短的pulse裡面
synchrotron radiation
可以產生比現在同步輻射
A Pulse height is almost 12 defenses
一個Pulse高大概幾乎是12次防的
Akiko Tamaki
多的晃子
So this light is very, very strong
所以這個光下去是非常非常強
and in a short time
而且又在很短的時間
So you can do some work related to time
所以你可以做一些跟時間有關係的工作
Video Programmers basically hope to use X-Ray to cover
影像的Program家基本上就希望用X-Ray來cover
to compensate for high-resolution, very high-resolution gaming
去彌補高解析度、非常高解析度的電競
What can be done with general medical imaging
跟一般醫學影像可以做的事情
i was hoping to talk
我本來是希望講的
I see like this when we should stop
我這樣看看什麼時候我們應該停止
Because each of these is an example of my own development
因為這個每個就是我自己的發展的例子
i just told you
我剛剛跟大家講
maybe today i know this maybe probably enough
也許今天我知道這個也許大概就夠了
this is caused
這個是造成
I feel like if I had a light come in
我覺得我如果有一個光進來
there is an edge here
這邊有一個邊緣的話
you will deflect the light slightly
你就會把這個光稍微偏折
so you're going to make this edge look like it's not
所以你會造成這個邊緣看起來就不是
If it was here, it would have absorbed so much
如果是這邊本來吸收這麼多
Here now it has a little bit of contrast
這邊現在它有一點點對比
But after this part like this
但是經過這樣子這個部分
After the change, the contrast will be stronger
變化以後對比就會比較強
Here is an example of a practical calculation
這是一個實際的計算的例子
Then you can see that this is the actual image
然後你可以看這是實際的影像
When I have a something like
當我有一個像這樣的東西
Here will produce very bright bright text
在這邊就會產生非常亮的亮文
then i have one
那我有一個
demonstration
demonstration
like this is
像這個就是
these are two rays
這是兩個光線
you can see it this distance
你可以看到它這個距離
When the distance from the detective is getting longer and longer
跟detective距離越來越長的時候
this edge will
這個邊緣會
at one stage it becomes very apparent
在一個階段會變得非常明顯
like this
像這樣
After a long time, it began to blur again
久了遠了以後它又開始變模糊
This is the most suitable time in its midst
這個在它中間最合適的時候
It is very powerful to use it as an image.
這個裡面拿來做影像是非常有力的
if you could have seen me go back to the beginning
就是本來你可以看到我回到從頭來的話
at the very beginning
剛開始的時候
You see, the edge is actually faint
你看這邊緣其實淡淡的
you can't see
你看不太到
But just taking this image alone
但是只是單獨把這個影像
This sample and your image
這個樣品跟你的影像
Whether it's negatives or not
不管是底片也好
CGD is also good
CGD也好
pull it away
把它拉遠一點
You can see its image slowly coming out
你就可以看到它這個影像慢慢的出來
that's what we're talking about
那這就是這個我們講的
One of the best demonstrations of Face contact
Face contact最好的一個demonstration
For example, at one centimeter
比如在一公分的時候
it will see very well
它這個就會看得很
It's clear that even these shafts in his middle
很清楚 連他的中間的這些軸
can see clearly
都可以看得很清楚
what's so important about this
那這個有什麼重要的
It's when you see your x-ray in the hospital
就是你看你在醫院做X-ray的時候
that radial it will make you cling
那個放射式它會叫你貼緊
The reason for the tight fit is simple
貼緊的原因就很簡單
I have one of these light sources today
我今天有一個這個光源
X-ray is a shadow graph
X-ray是一個shadow graph
just look at the shadow
就是看影子
so i put my hands here now
所以我現在手放在這邊
light source like you now
你現在這樣子的光源
Your edge must not be...
你邊緣一定不...
But if you go outside
可是你如果到室外
if you go to see the sun
你去看太陽光的話
you are so chic
你邊緣就很瀟
have you ever wondered why
你們想過為什麼
It's because the light source is too diffuse
就是因為這個光源太發散
because it borders
因為它邊緣
There are photos here
這邊也有照這邊
So you can draw straight lines
所以你可以畫直線
you'll know it's edge
你就會知道它邊緣
will be fully illuminated
會被整個照到
So say this way
所以說這個樣的方式
That is to say, even if you are on the edge
就是說你即使邊緣
have this strengthening effect
有這個強化的效果
also be affected by the poor quality of your light source
也會被你光源的差的品質
wash it off
把它洗掉
so at this time
所以在這個時候
that is usually
就是說通常
You want it to be brimless
你希望它邊緣不要牛虎虎
you hope higher
你希望越高
so you can watch
就叫你可以看
My shadow is getting clearer and clearer
我這樣影子越來越清楚
By this time the edges are clear
到這個時候邊緣就很清楚了
then it is very simple
那這是很簡單的
You can know this geometry
這個幾何你就可以知道
then we now
那我們現在
But the problem is that we were just talking about
可是問題就是我們剛剛在講說
This refraction is also different
這個折射也不一樣
refract me when a thing passes by
折射我當一個東西經過去
Its refraction is to deflect this angle
它折射是偏折這個角度
is the difference in your refractive index
是跟你的折射率的差異
Into justice
成正理
at small angles
在小角度的時候
So its refractive index
所以說它的折射率
This S light all things
這個S光所有的東西
There is very little difference with air
跟空氣的差異都很少
is the square of ten
是十的四字方
is the refractive index of its air
就是它空氣的折射率
if one
如果是一的話
has the refractive index of water
有水的折射率
We are 1.0001
我們就是1.0001
One ten-thousandth of 0.99994
0.99994的萬分之一
or one in a hundred thousand
或者是十萬分之一
So denoting its deflection pilot
所以表示它的偏折機師
you now make a ball
你現在做成一個球
a water ball
一個水的球
or a glass ball
或者一個玻璃球
When this S light passes through
這個S光穿過的時候
It deflects at a very, very small angle
它的偏折的角度非常非常小
But we want to see its edge imaging
可是我們又希望看到它邊緣成像
what are you going to do
那你要怎麼做
very simple
講得很簡單
I will pull the distance away
我就把距離拉遠
Originally it was this deflection, this Chen Xiaolou
本來是這個偏折這個陳曉樓
pull it away
拉遠了它就
Zoom in on the resolution of my detector
放大了 我的這個探測器的解析度
start can catch say
開始可以抓到說
I have light and dark spots on the edges
我這個邊緣是有亮跟暗斑的時候
The shape of the whole thing will be highlighted
這個整個東西的它外型就會被凸顯出來
But if you don't have a good light source
但是你如果沒有好的光源的時候
you have a problem
你就有問題了
You zoom out and your image becomes blurred
你拉遠 你的影像就變模糊
it washes the edge off
它把這個邊緣通通洗掉了
So this is why we now
所以這個是為什麼我們現在
we are what we are
我們就是我們在
I was talking about this Face Country ten years ago
十年前在講這個Face Country
We also had a press conference
我們也有開過記者會
At that time everyone asked me
那時候每個人問我說
When can Face Country be used in the hospital?
Face Country什麼時候可以拿到醫院去用
let's say five years
我們說要五年吧
It's been ten years now
到現在已經十年完了
You're asking me maybe I can still talk for five years?
你在問我可能還是可以講五年吧
that is to say, where is the reason
就是說原因在哪裡
That is, we except the synchronous subsidiary
就是我們除了同步輔社
Besides such a good light source
這麼好的光源以外
I can't find any other substitute students
再也找不到其他的替代的同學
I just told you that
我剛剛跟大家講就是
I am actually our light source
我其實我們的光源
The first is that it requires collimation to be a bit
第一個就是它的要求準直性是一位
We only need its light source to be small enough
我們只要需要它的光源夠小
So today I put a
所以我今天把一個
put in a fight
放在一個拼後
put it on an open eye put it on
放在一個睜眼 放上去
This light source is like a point
這個光源就像是點
You can see that the edges will be very clear
你可以看到它的邊緣就會很清晰
The only problem is when you put
唯一的問題就是當你放到這個時候
You have no intensity, you have no light
你就沒有intense 你就沒有光了
light becomes a little bit
光變成一點點
The advantage of synchrotron radiation is that
同步輻射的好處就是
My light source is very small but it's very collimated
我的光源又很小 但是它又很準直
is that I can send one like we do now
就是我可以送一個像我們現在做的
Our light source represents 100mc
我們的光源代表100mc
as thick as hair
像頭髮這麼粗細的
placed 30 meters away
放在30公尺以外
When you look at it with the naked eye, it looks like a point light source
你肉眼去看 它就像是點光源
But it sends the light to you when you need it
可是它把光送到你這個要用的時候
it won't spread
它又不會發散
You can think of me if a single point light source
你可以想到我如果一個單獨點光源
It is 1 over R squared
它是1 over R squared
It says to follow the distance of R
它就說跟著R的距離情況
When you walk 30 meters away, its already gone
你走到你30公尺早就沒有了
this is what we've been waiting for
這個是我們一直在等
hope you say there is a good light source
希望你說有很好的光源
this has always been
這個一直是
Many people have always thought
一直有很多人認為
can be done in this way
可以這樣的方式可以做
but we waited so long
但是我們等了這麼久
Actually quite disappointed
其實還滿失望的
That is to say, now
就是說其實現在
so far very few
到現在還很少
This is an example
這個是一個例子
That's what they do with hair radiation
就是他們這個是用頭髮輻射做
I have separate comparative
我單獨有相對比的
Just do a separate five-party photography
就做單獨的五方攝影
what difference would you make
你會有什麼差異
this is not
這個是沒有
It is conventional
就是conventional
Tradition
傳統
This is done with face contrast mammography
這個是用face contrast mammography做的
you can see
你可以看到
Of course, this place also stands out
當然這個地方它也凸顯起來
It's not because of its Western state differences
它不是因為它的西州的差異
This is made by a Japanese Konika
這個是一家日本的Konika做的
They are also called face contrast mammography
他們也叫做face contrast mammography
but this
但是這個
Has not been used by many people
一直沒有很多人在用
we're asking general practitioners
我們在問一般醫生
They don't even know it exists
他們根本不知道有這個東西
so i was thinking
所以我在想
is the benefit it may get
就是它可能得到的好處
Not as much as they advertise
並不是像他們自己廣告的那麼多
So doctors don't have much interest in doing this
所以醫生沒有太大的興趣做這個事
The face contrast mammography
這個face contrast mammography
Let me give another very simple example
我再舉一個很簡單的例子
like this
像這個
this is
這個就是
This is the heart of a mouse
這是一個小鼠的心臟
a part
一個部分
at this distance
在這個距離的時候
you look like
你看起來
In fact, so-and-so tiger
其實某某虎虎
this black place
這個黑色的地方
is inside its heart
是它心臟裡面
we specifically make it
我們特別讓它
This structure that grows lidification
長出蓋化的這個結構
capping structure
這個蓋化結構
just to come
為了就是要來個
Simulate this non-coming situation
模擬這個不來的狀況
because the mice didn't come in
因為小鼠沒有入來
Although you use its breast cancer cells
雖然你用的是它乳癌的細胞
But you can't grow breast cancer like a human
但是你長不出像人一樣的乳癌的狀況
Therefore, it cannot be used as an example of video
所以不能拿來做影像的這個例子
But here we do
但是在這個我們就做了
with different distances
用不同的距離
You go to see me just to distance you
你去看我只是把距離拉遠
You can look at these structures and suddenly run out
你可以看這些結構就忽然一下跑出來
see clearly
看得很清楚
Then this is the biggest benefit of doing this Face Contrast
那這也是就做這個Face Contrast最大的好處
like this too
像這也是一樣
You see, after the distance is extended
你看距離拉長了以後
its image is very clear
它的影像就很清楚
For example, what I just said just now is that
那譬如說剛剛我剛剛講的就是說
You can see that these two are actually poor in contrast.
你看這兩個本身其實是它的對比差的
not so much
不是那麼多
But because of the efficiency of refraction at the edges
但是因為邊緣的折射的效率
After the effect, you can see its edge very clearly
效果以後你可以看到它這個邊緣就看得非常清楚
Then you can see that we use this way
那你可以看到我們用這個方式
You can see this bubble above
可以看到這個bubble上面
In fact, it is the structure of the metal that grows
其實是長了這個金屬的這個結構
because it has metal connections with electrical connections
因為它有金屬的連有電路的連結
ok
ok
Okay, the rest of the following are some demonstrations
好的這下面其他都是一些demonstration
Then here are some comparisons we made with fossils
那這是我們做的一些跟化石跟相對比
not much relationship
沒有太多的關係
But the business name is important
但是商號它很重要
So Polish is in Size
所以Polish在Size
ok
ok
Here's another job we did
這是我們做的另外一個工作
even it was a long time ago
就是它也是很早以前的
Fossil of this embryo from 540 million years ago
五億四千萬年前的這個胚胎的化石
Then this is our relationship with Professor Li Jiawei of Tsinghua University
那這是我們跟清華大學李嘉維教授
when cooperating
在合作的時候
He said he found a lot of these sheds in here
他就說他發覺這裡面有很多這些棚道
this is a fossil
這是一顆化石
this fossil is small
這個化石很小
Because it's an embryo kind of like that Kentin
因為這是胚胎有點像那個肯丁
For example, when the coral is spawning,
比如說那個珊瑚在產卵的時候
Then this is in the southwest of the mainland
然後這個是在大陸西南
That is when the geological movement
那就是在地質運動的時候
may be spawning in this
可能正在這個產卵
Others suddenly the earth's crust becomes passive
其他忽然一下地殼被動起來
all frozen in time by all these things
全部都被所有這些東西都 frozen in time
come out like this
出來就變成像這個樣子
Then the size of this one is about
那麼這一顆的大小大概
550.5 This is useless
五百五百零點五個這個毫無儀座用
OK then we did a lot more
OK 那我們還做了其他很多
early days
早期的時候
Like this fly head
比如像這個蒼蠅頭
I put it where we say
我把它放在我們說
Because this is actually a beautiful picture of clam worms
因為這個其實是蚌蚓漂亮的一個圖
That is to say, the whole head of a fly
就是說這個整個蒼蠅的頭
you can tell it's inside
你可以看得出來它裡面
So I have the structure of the first detail
所以我有第一細節的結構
But like this we can
但是就像這個我們可以
Reconstructed tomography
重組出來的斷層掃描
you can see his head very clearly
你可以看他的頭很清楚
But you say it's nothing
但是你說這沒什麼了不起
with this electron microscope
用這個電子顯微鏡
You can see clearly with this scanning electron microscope
這個掃描電鏡你可以看得很清楚
But what the SEM can't do is
但是掃描電鏡做不到的是
he can't see inside yet
他還看不到裡面
So we can reorganize
所以我們可以在重組的時候
we can do whatever
我們可以任意的
because it's a model
因為這是一個模型
Although this is a model
雖然這是一個模型
This is a very accurate model
這是一個非常精確的模型
It is the model with the same resolution as yours
就是跟你的解析度一樣的模型
after you make it
你做出來以後
you can go in any direction
你可以在任意的方向去
Just like you did this tomography in the hospital
就跟你在醫院做了這個斷層掃描
you don't need to stay there anymore
你不需要再待在那裡
From now on, he keeps looking at this picture of him
下面他就一直看他這個圖
He can find where he wants to look
他就可以找到他想要看的地方
ok
ok
there's some of this
那有一些這個
wow
wow
Then I won't talk about how I did it
那我這些怎麼做的我就不講
I'm in this now
我現在這個裡面
we have to advertise
我們要廣告一下就是說
We're going to do a good resolution
我們要做很好的解析度
I just said that
剛剛我剛剛講就是說
video like this
像這樣子的影像方式
Your resolution is up to you on this catapult
你解析度是決定在你的這個彈射器
today i will take this with me
今天我就跟我這個
Take a CCD to do it
拿一個CCD去做
It shines at this time, because your light has a very short wavelength
它這個時候照出來,因為你的光是波長很短的
I just said that after the light passes through
我剛剛講它這個光穿過去以後
This image does not cause resolution issues
這影像不會造成解析度的問題
But at this time the resolution is limited to your detector
而是這時候解析度是限制在你的detector
So I take a CCD one by one
所以我一個拿一個CCD
You said above that I am sensitive to S-light CCD
上面你說我對S光感光的CCD
When you go, your pixel determines your resolution
去的時候你的pixel你的這個像素就決定了你的解析度
So today if you talk about this semiconductor company
所以我你今天如果說這個半導體公司
This CCD can be made into a CMOS
可以做一個CMOS的這個CCD
is this pixel with 20 nanometers
是有20奈米的這個像素
My resolution is 20nm
我的解析度就是20奈米
this do s light
這做S光
But this can't be done now
但是這個現在現在做不到
Now look at the specifications of your cameras
現在你看你們去看你們相機的這個這個規格
About two or three microns
大概都是兩三micron左右
So this is actually what we do and that
所以這也是其實我們這樣做也是那個
Then the other way is my S light
那另外一個辦法就是我S光
Can't I zoom in on it first
我難道不能先把它放大的以後
I'll use this detector to pick it up again
我再去用這個探測器去接
like this
這樣子的話
Because you said I am zooming in
因為你說我這放大
It will not affect the resolution of your intrinsic itself
不會影響你的這個intrinsic本身的解析度
Then I am at this time, you are originally a micron resolution
那我這時候你本來是一micron的解析度
If I enlarge the resolution to 20 times
解析度我如果放大成20倍
i can get 20 times
我就可以得到20倍
It becomes 50nm 50nm resolution
就变成50nm 50nm的解析度
why do you do that
那为什么这样做
The reason is that the S-light Lens is very, very difficult to make
原因就是说S光的Lens非常非常难做
Because S light penetrates everything
因为S光它什么东西都穿透
it is not pleated
它也不偏褶
You take one through it and it ignores you
你拿一个透进去它也不理你
Then you want the other reflective way
然后你要其他反射的方式
it's slightly angled
它角度稍微大一点
it just goes through
它就通通穿过去了
so it becomes very difficult to do
所以变成非常难做
The only device that everyone agrees is better
那唯一大家公认比较好的一个Device
That is, if you are on the bus
就是说你们如果在公车上
Sometimes there is a magnifying glass behind the bus
公车有时候后面有一个放大镜
It looks like a ring
一看来像一环一环的
That's the Fone Lens we're talking about
那就是我们在讲的Fone Lens
that part
那这个部分
how well that thing is done
那个东西做得多好
depends on your resolution
跟你的解析度有关系
The size of its outermost circle is related to your resolution
它最外圈的大小就跟你的解析度有关
then i just said
那我刚刚讲说
If we reach the best 15nm
我们达到最好的15nm的话
that outer circle
那个外圈
We want to achieve a line block of almost 20nm
我们要做到差不多20nm的线块
Then at 20nm it has to be very high
然后20nm它要做到非常高
Because you want to have an effect on S light
因为你要对S光有效果
you are going to build a wall
你要蓋一個牆
For example, a height of 500 nanometers
比如說是500奈米的高度
But the width of 20 nanometers
但是20奈米的寬度
Then you still use gold to fill it up
然後這個東西你還用金去把它填起來
So the difficulty of this is very high
所以這個的難度是非常高
I'd say we've challenged before
我就說我們以前挑戰過
For example, we are supplying TSMC
比如說我們在給套給台積電
I said we TSMC, you can't do this
我說我們台積電你就做不到這一點
Because TSMC they made this device
因為台積電他們做的這個device
Can do ten or twenty nanometers
可以做十幾二十奈米
But its S5 ratio is very low
但是它的這個S5 ratio很低
And they do ten or twenty nanometers
而且他們做十幾二十奈米
It's the FaceShift way
它是用FaceShift的方式
It can't do Grading
它沒有辦法做Grading
That is to say, I can't do continuous
就是說我沒有辦法做連續
Twenty empty twenty results like this
二十空的二十這樣子的結果
It can only say I do a big one like this
它只能說我做一個大的這樣
Edge I can do it well done it becomes like that
邊緣我可以做到它做得很清楚變成像那樣
Then the device made is
那做的這個device是
because we have a really nice nike process inside the lock
因為我們鎖裡面有一個非常好的這個耐克製程
that this is this is a
那這個是這個是一個
that is to say we are saying
就是說我們在說
Rarely have this one this in the whole world
在全世界很少有這個一個這個
A department like this can look like this
系所這種單位可以有這樣子的
equipment like this
這樣子的設備
then we are lucky too
那我們也很幸運
There is this thing to support us
有這個東西支持我們做
So we made this Device like this
所以我們就做了像這樣子的這個Device
Then come as a magnifying glass
然後來當一個放大鏡
This is the magnifying glass of S1
這就是S1的放大鏡
When this S1 passes by
當這個S1經過的時候
you use this magnifying glass
你用這個放大鏡
Then project it onto this CCD
再把它投影到這個CCD上
Your resolution is
你的解析度就是
Divide your resolution by
你這個解析度再除以
your magnification
你這個放大的倍率
Then make this Device
那這個Device做起來
I just said like this
我剛剛講就像這個樣子
This is the outermost circle inside
這個裡面最外圈的
smallest possible
可能最小的
We can do 20nm
我們可以做到20nm
Its height is 450nm
它的高度是450nm
Then this is with gold seat
然後這是用金座的
Because the absorption of gold is the strongest
因為金的吸收是最強的
Then it's the best time to do it
那這做出來裡面做到最好的時候
just like
就是像
This is a Lens that looks like this
這是一個用這樣子的這個Lens
to make an image
去做一個影像的話
Like this is our test
像這是我們的測試的
What a pattern test looks like
Pattern 測試的樣子
the innermost one
那這個最裡面的這個
each of this structure
每一個這個結構
is this interval of 30nm
是30nm的這個間隔
So we can clearly see
所以我們可以很清楚的看到
means that our resolution
就表示我們這個解析度
Should be better than 30nm
應該是比30nm還好
So we did another
所以我們又做了其他
His test is like we made a structure ourselves
他的測試是說像我們自己做了一個結構
The innermost is 20nm
最裡面是20nm
You can see that this is actually a good result
你可以看到這其實還是很好的result
It's good to be able to parse it out
很好的就可以解析出來
It means that our resolution should still be better than 20nm
表示我們的解析度應該還是比20nm好
So we put a lot of effort into doing
所以我們花了很多功夫去做
Finally decided to say that we look at it with a different structure
才最後決定說我們用不同的結構去看的話
Let's look at his analysis
我們看他分析的狀況
calculated in a strict way
用很嚴格的方式算出來
So our resolution is about 16nm
所以我們的解析度大概是16nm左右
16nm
16nm
This means that we are doing X-ray like this now
這個就是說是現在在做這樣子的X-ray
Still no one can do a structure like this
還是沒有人可以做到像這樣子的結構
I give an example
我舉個例子
We originally published an article a while ago
我們原來前一陣子發表一篇文章
We actually started doing this structure in 2006
我們其實從2006年開始做這樣的結構
Resolution from earliest to last
從最早開始以至的解析度
Come down from the secular generation, the Mishi, and the eleventh degree
從世俗代、米世、十一度下來
We can do it for about 16 years now
到現在我們大概可以做到16年
In fact, since this
其實從這個開始以後
In fact, we are of course proud to say that
其實我們當然驕傲的是說
from this onwards
從這個開始以後
a world structure
一個都是世界結構
it no one can do like this
它沒有人可以做這樣
So we used the equipment of the middle actor all the way
所以我們一路用的這個中演員的這個設備
do it now we are
做到現在我們是
Now we can do this to the extent that this has become
現在可以做到這個這個變成的程度
OK
OK
I'll just skip the part about rice granules
那個耐米顆粒的部分我就跳過去
I'm at the end
那我在最後
Let me show you a few examples
給大家給你們看幾個例子
I don't explain like this is a
我不要解釋像這個是一個
Let's do a lower resolution version of this
我們做比較低解析度的這個
you think
你想
OK
OK
This is an example of our cooperation with these three Chengan physicians
這是一個我們跟這個三種成安醫師合作的一個例子
That is to say, he is studying this long-term kidney disease
就是說他是研究這個長期腎病
I think you probably know why we study long-term kidney disease
我想你們大概都知道為什麼我們要研究長期腎病
Because Taiwan is the devil king of kidney dialysis
因為台灣是洗腎王魔王
Kidney dialysis alone will wash away 80 billion
光是洗腎一年要洗掉800億
So and most of the reasons are
那所以而且大部分的原因都是
Go and take those medicines that invigorate the kidneys
去亂吃那些補腎的藥
Caused
造成的
OK
OK
This is a normal small genus of kidney
這是一個正常的小屬的腎臟
You can see it every one of this kidney bulb
你可以看到它每一個這個腎濕球
The glomerulus can be seen clearly
腎小球都可以看得清清楚楚
blood vessels are fine
血管都很好
every one is clean
每一個都是乾乾淨淨的
so you can see the secret mama
所以你可以看到祕密麻麻
we can even say
我們甚至可以算說
This whole little one is like this
這整個小屬這樣
Its glomeruli may have seven to eight thousand
它這個腎小球可能有七八千個
But if you say like this example
但是你如果說是像這個例子
That is to say, this is a disease they created.
就是說這個是他們製造出來的疾病
It's called a long-term kidney disease in this mouse.
就叫做這個小鼠的一個長期腎病
You can see that most of the glomeruli are gone
你可以看到大部分的腎小球都不見了
only a small part remains
只有小部分還在
because it if not
因為它如果沒有的話
the mouse won't live
小鼠就活不了了
Most of the glomeruli have disappeared
那大部分的腎小球都已經消失了
It doesn't matter if it is inflamed
就它不管是發炎也好
or it is blocked
或者是它堵住也好
Then there are only these water-quality blood vessels in the middle
那只剩下中間這些水質的血管
Contains only a small portion of this kidney
只含一些小部分的這個腎
So it's obvious to tell you
所以這很明顯就可以跟大家講說
We can study this way
我們可以用這個方式來研究
Otherwise they're going to slice
否則的話他們要去切片
After you cut each slice you're going to slice
你每片切完以後你要去一片
look how much it has in it
你看它到底裡面有多少
this thing is troublesome
這東西是很麻煩
It's not easy for you to quantify
你也不容易做定量
Now we do it like this
現在我們這樣做一個這樣的這個
this tomography
這個斷層掃描
They agree that they can calculate and say
他們很同意就可以計算說
what condition am i in
我在什麼樣的狀況
what a day it will be
它多好天以後
how did it die
它是怎麼死的
That is, these glomeruli are
就是說這些腎小球是
dead song by song
一曲一曲死的呢
Still getting bad one by one
還是一個一個變壞的
this is doing this to them
這個是對它們做這個
this is very helpful
這很有幫助的
Another thing we do is look at the nerves
我們另外做的一個就是看神經
This is our cooperation with the essence-related characters
這是跟我們跟精華相關式角色合作
We hope that the use of S-light can turn silver
我們希望使用S光能夠把過銀
or even the nerves in the mouse
或者甚至小鼠它裡面的神經
completely by way of tomography
完全用斷層掃描的方式
start it all at once with a neuro hospital
一次把它全部從神經醫院開始
to various links
到各種的連結
Go to these Dendrites all at once and get it done
到這些Dendrite全部一次把它做完
This project is what we want to send
這個project就是我們要發的
In fact, the most important skill is not in the technology of S beauty
其實最重要功夫其實不是在S美的技術
Just like what we just said
就跟我們剛剛大家講的
how do you dye
你怎麼樣染色
How about Administrate your developer
怎麼樣Administrate你的這個顯影劑
with your calibration
跟你的標定
This is actually the most difficult
這個其實反而是最困難
because we already told you
因為我們這已經告訴你說
You just have to dye it so we can see it
你只要染得到我們就可以看得到
You can see its smallest structure
可以看到它最細微的結構
These little ones are its Dendrite
這些小小的都是它的Dendrite
It cannot be seen in an optical microscope.
在光學顯微鏡裡面也是看不到的
OK
OK
I think I've probably said a lot more than that.
我想我大概已經講超過很多了
I'll just stop here
我就在這邊停一下
Unless you all are interested in seeing other
除非你們大家也興趣看其他的
Maybe
也許
OK
OK
all that's left to do is watch
剩下的就是看
Do you have any questions here?
在座有沒有任何的問題
Just now I
我剛剛
First of all, thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
那先謝謝老師精采的演講
The question I want to ask is
我想請教的問題是
Just like the hand-held laser device that the teacher used to give a speech today
就像老師今天演講用的手持的雷射設備一樣
You can take a laser light gun with your hand
就是手持就可以拿雷射光槍照
So the laser light can be from such a large
所以雷射光這樣可以從那麼大的
What was originally a raw device becomes a handheld device
原先的原始的設備變成一個手持的設備
Synchronized X-rays and lasers
那同步X光這種雷射
It currently has no way to become minified
它目前沒有辦法變成縮小的
And what is the reason for the device that is very effective and usable
而且很有效可以使用的裝置的理由是什麼
Another thing I want to ask is
那另外一個想請教的是
Just now you mentioned three more times
剛才你有再三個提到
The teacher's team has the world's first technology
老師的團隊有世界第一的技術
But just now in your slideshow
但是剛才在您的投影片
You also mentioned that these devices are finally used
您也提到終於運用的這些設備
It's all like a touch
都是像一Touch
or some commercially available equipment
或一些商業上就買得到的設備
what's the reason
那是什麼理由
Said that other units that can also buy these devices
說其他也能買到這些設備的單位
they can't do these things
他們做不到這些事情
Teacher He can do this
何老師這段可以做到這件事情
I think the latter question
我想後面這個問題
what i say is what you say
我講的就是你講的
That is to say, his optical Lens
就是說他光學這個Lens
This fact is
這個事其實
If you say yes, no one else will do it
你如果說是別人都不會做
only we will do
只有我們會做
it's a little stretched
這有點拖大
We can only say that others are too lazy to do it
我們只能說別人懶得做
or no one else wants to do
或者別人沒有想要做
In fact, I will tell our own students
其實我再跟我們自己學生講
The biggest reason is
最大的原因就是
we have no one else
我們有別人沒有
others can buy
別人可以買
but others
但是別人
For example, TSMC has similar
譬如說台積電也有類似的
This Evil Writer
這個Evil Writer
But his job is very fixed
但是他的工作是很固定的
i am a friend
我跟我一個朋友
He originally started this company
他是原來開這個公司
Just do this S-Wang Shen Wei Jing
就是做這個S-Wang Shen Wei Jing的
I tell him
我跟他講
you can't compete with us
你沒有辦法跟我們競爭
Why
為什麼
because you are a company
因為你是公司
you want to profit
你要將本求利
i bought something
我買了一個東西
even if you do the same thing
即使你做同樣的東西
he wants to count
他要算
So they didn't buy it themselves
所以他們自己都沒有買
Evil Writer
Evil Writer
he borrowed this one
他借這個一個
he's in california he borrowed this
他在加州他借這個
Use this E-BING RIDER
用這個E-BING RIDER
one thousand dollars an hour
一個小時要一千美金
because this is the machine
因為這個是這個機器
When Zhongyuan Industry first bought it,
我們中原業當初買的時候就
Hundreds of millions soon
快上億呀
that for us
那對我們來講
I just said you know we last year
我就說你知道我們去年
Thousands a year
一年用幾千
we use
我們用
6 to 7 thousand hours
6到7千個小時
So only used in E-BING RIDER
所以光是用在E-BING RIDER
you buy outside
你在外面買
so i say you can't compete
所以我就說你沒有辦法競爭
Because this is what we are doing research we
因為這個是我們是做研究我們
The thing is here, we don't need to think about it every day
東西在了我們不需要考慮每天去算說這個
I use
我用的
So we are not saying that it takes 6,000 an hour to make this device
所以我們不是說要花6千一個小時做這一個device
But we spent a lot of energy from 0 to nothing
而是我們花了很多精神從0到沒有
to learn
去學
It's all these young people who go in slowly and cover their whole body, and then go slowly to fiddle with it.
都是這些年輕人慢慢進去全身包的然後去慢慢去弄弄弄
None of this can be taught
這些都沒有人可以教的
touch it out so it can be done
摸出來所以可以做
so this is
所以這個是
I think this is where you say why we
我想這個是你如果要講說為什麼我們
pretty sure
很有把握說
no one is doing it now
現在沒有人在做的
do like us
做得像我們這樣
because when you do
因為當你做了以後
It's easy for the people behind to do it
後面的人要做就很容易
When we first started doing
在最早我們剛開始做的時候
That is to say, at 100nm
就是說100nm的時候
when i was a graduate student
我在做研究生的時候
We know this kind of device
我們就知道這種device
We never thought to say that today S1
我們從來沒想到說今天S1
Can do 100nm
可以做到100nm
I said where is that possible?
我說哪裡有可能那個
but why we do it
但是我們為什麼我們做就
Because people have already done it
因為人家已經做成了
when people have made
當人家已經做成
it's easy when you're doing
你在做的時候就很容易
you know it will work
你知道一定做得成
Then when we make it
那當我們做成以後
Our students are interested in
我們這些學生有興趣
young people are interested
年輕的人有興趣
He kept touching and touching
他就一直摸一直摸摸
I found that the more I did the better, the better I did it
發覺越做越好越做越好
this is
這個是
The other one is that you have something to play with you there
另外一個是你要有東西在那跟你玩
so this is
所以這個是
maybe that's kinda
可能就是說有點是
does not match the cost
跟這個成本不合
If it were the vice president today, tell me
今天如果是這個副院長跟我講說
You see you spend $6 million a year
你看你們花了600萬美金一年
do this thing
做這個東西
As a result, none of them were sold.
結果一個都賣不出去
then there is no way to do it
那就沒辦法做了
and the front is
還有前面是
I think it's because of the intractability of X-ray
我想這就是因為X-ray難處理的
Even if you have a laser, you usually also have a resonance gun
就是你一個雷射通常也會有一個共振槍
you need this thing in it
你這個東西要在裡面
I want to oscelate and resonate in it
我要在裡面可以oscelate,可以resonate
This X-ray doesn't have it
這X-ray沒有啊
I'm getting a metal box now
我現在弄一個金屬的盒子
It goes out with a swipe
它巴一下就出去啦
and now it uses shreds, they now use electrons to go
然後現在它用碎,它們現在用電子去
make it some coherence
讓它有一些相干性
For example, after my electron comes in
比如說我這電子進來以後
I use a magnetic field to make it go to the module
我用一個磁場讓它去module
The magnetic field module will slowly lose together
那磁場module它會慢慢會輸在一起
After inputting together, it interacts with electrons
輸在一起以後它電子跟電子的interaction
it ends up having some coperance, some coherence
它最後會變成有一些coperance,有一些相干性
In the end they all feel that they shine together
最後它們大家覺得一起放光
At this time, the light is a bit like a laser.
這時候的光就有點像是雷射
That part, this is where they are
那這個部分,這個就他們也在
Everyone is thinking, what Stanford did in the beginning was a few kilometers
每個人都在想啊,以前剛開始Stanford做的是幾公里的
plus the one shot of free electrons made in Europe
加歐洲做的那個自由電子的一射
it's five kilometers
這是五公里
The 700 meters that Japan is doing now
日本現在做的700公尺
Then Switzerland and South Korea may be 200 meters away
然後瑞士跟韓國他們可能200公尺就有
So I was thinking that if it is possible to achieve 100 meters or 50 meters
所以我在想如果說做到100公尺或者是50公尺是很有可能的
But it's hard to do it this way
但是就是說很難這種方式你很難做到
like this
像這樣
How can TSMC still try to accumulate iron from the CCP?
台積電還是怎麼要向中共來試積的把鐵而已
Which step does Taiwan not understand or do not know how to do?
台灣是哪一個步驟不懂或不會做
Why do you have to buy some trial product material from the CCP?
為什麼要一定要向中共買什麼試積的material
interaction first
interaction first
I haven't researched this, so I can't just talk about it
這個我沒有研究我不能隨便亂講
But I think if TSMC's technology is the best in the world
但是我覺得如果台積電的技術是世界上非常好的
I think Director Yang may know better
我想整個楊主任可能會知道比較清楚一點
So they went to buy from the CCP, I think it may be the only one
所以他們去跟這個中共買我覺得可能唯一
One reason is that it is cheaper
一個原因就是要比較便宜吧
yeah i don't think so
對啊 我不覺得這個
OK, of course the Chinese Communist Party has
OK 中共當然有
When I often go to the mainland, I find that there are many of them
我常常去大陸的時候發覺他們是有很多
For example, the SWET detector I just talked about
比如我剛剛講的SWET detector
No. 3 they also do
3號他們也有做
Infrared detector they also do business
Infrared detector 他們生意也有做
But you can't tell they're selling
但是你也看不出來他們在賣
These are military industries
這些都是軍工產業
this they all
這個他們都是
But other than this for commercial use
但除了這個以外做商用的
They have nothing better to do than use
他們沒有東西做得比用 好嗎
so they are giving
所以他們在給
I don't think there's anything to worry about
我覺得這個沒有什麼好擔心的
they buy our stuff
他們買我們的東西
I'm afraid it's a lot more than I buy from them.
恐怕比我買他們東西多很多吧
Teacher Wu just mentioned that
吳老師剛剛正提到那個
The image I want to see the most
我最想看的那個影像
Lung cancer detection
Lung cancer detection
introduce that paragraph
把那段介紹
Because the question I want to ask is this Scale in Sale
因為我要問的問題是在Sale的這個Scale
You can also have XX to see
一樣可以有XX看
Is there a structure in Sale?
Sale裡面的結構嗎
Thanks
謝謝
This is actually not a very successful work in mice
這個其實在小鼠這個不是一個很成功的工作
Because we were talking about comparison at the beginning, in fact, looking at this Lung is very good
因為我們當初在講說相對比其實看這個Lung是非常好
You can theorize that we are all pieces of this picture put together
你可以理論我們這個都是拼起來的圖
In fact, you can zoom in and see very clearly
其實你可以放大看非常清楚
That mouse is actually alive
那這個小鼠其實是活的
You can see because when we put together song by song
你可以看到因為我們在一張一張曲的時候拼的時候
jump it and move
跳它再動
So look at the rib we didn't even get it right
所以你看這個肋骨我們都沒有接好
We put it like this on purpose
我們故意放在這樣
But you can see Lung and the T-shirt outside
但是你可以看到Lung跟外面的T-shirt
its texture
它的Texture
This is the image of it
就是它的這個影像出來的這個
The latter structure looks obviously different
後面的這個結構看起來很明顯就不太一樣
And while you have a solid this in here
那同時你在這裡面有一個固體的這個
Words of dense tissue Tumor
密實組織的Tumor的話
Logically speaking, it should be easy
照理講是應該很容易
So there is no processing here
所以這裡面沒有處理
that's how we see it
我們就是為了這樣看
Show it to the doctor
給醫生可以看
Then you can see it in my Circle
那你可以看到在我Circle裡面
draw it
畫出來
This is a Tumor we entered to make it grow
這個是我們打進去的一個Tumor讓它長的
Then you can see like I zoom in white
那你可以看到像我放大白
I said you don't know if you can see and see
我說你不知道看得見看得見
Here is a Tumor
這邊是一個Tumor
Then you don't know if you can see and see
那你不知道看得見看得見
There is a Tumor over here
這邊是有一個Tumor
Then you can see the very grainy one inside it.
那你可以看它這裡面這種很顆粒狀的這個
It is because the lungs are lung cannons one by one
就是因為肺裡面它是一個一個肺炮
Of course it's a lung cannon and we're not here
當然它肺炮並不是我們在這裡
lung cannon
呈向著肺炮
but lung cannon it this
而是肺炮它這個
How about it
怎麼樣
Changed the direction of your light
調變了你的這個光的行徑的方向
Come out and make you feel like this swish
出來讓你感覺像是這樣子沙沙烏烏的
that this is its this
那這個是它的這個
So this is about 3mm
所以這個是一個大概3mm左右
It's still about 2mm for this hall door
還是2mm左右的這個廳門
But we can also do this
不過我們也可以做這個
About 0.7mm hall door
大概0.7mm的廳門
right here
就在這裡面
It's actually pretty easy to see
這其實是很容易看
But this paper we always hope to send this
但是這個paper我們一直希望送給這個
We call it radiology
我們叫radiology
Just do this method, this, this journal
就是做這個方式性的這個這個journal
no one to believe
沒有人要相信
None of them talk about 0.7mm
他們都不講說0.7mm
Is this small in people
難道這個在人是很小
But the decimal is still quite large
但是在小數還是蠻大的
You can see the decimals are not necessarily
你可以看到小數不見得
you can see in person
你可以在人看到
Then these journal medical journals are made for people
那這些journal medical journal就是為人做的
He doesn't care about you doing decimal stuff
他不care about你在做小數的東西
yes
對啊
then this is
那這個是
We actually put a lot of effort into
我們其實花了很多功夫
make it as possible
讓它盡量可以
you can see like here
你可以看到像這裡
This is caused by the face contract
這個就是face contract造成
its first its edges are clearly visible
它第一個它的邊緣看得很清楚
The second is this structure inside
第二個是裡面的這個結構
It's not the same as the muscle on the outside
跟外面這個肌肉的不太一樣
So if there is a
所以中間如果出現一個
tissue like meat
像是肉一樣的組織
It's actually easy to see
其實是很容易看
This doesn't need any processing
這個不需要做任何處理
I just said that this is called a natural contract
我剛剛就說這個是叫做natural contract
Because the lungs are mostly air
因為肺裡面大部分是空氣
Part of it is a lung cannon like this
有一部分是這樣的肺炮
and now you have a lump of meat in the middle
然後你現在中間有一坨肉
In fact, it is easy to say
其實照理講是很容易
easily distinguishable
很容易區別的
I can show you
我可以給大家看
This is normal
這個是正常的
you can see this lung
你可以看到這個肺
see quite clearly
看得蠻清楚
This middle is this heart
這個中間是這個心臟
This is how we can
這個是我們就這樣子可以
The problem with applying it to people is that
用到人身上的問題是說
still no face contract
還是沒有face contract
There is no hospital yet
現在醫院還沒有
Can we get people
那我們能不能把人
Bring it to Synchro
帶到同步輔社去做
This Europe has done a lot
這個歐洲已經做了很多
someone made this
有人做了這個
with aluminum anti-photography
有鋁防攝影的
Then there is this cardiovascular noise
然後有做這個心血管噪影的
All these prove that the imaging of synchronous radiation
這些都證明同步輔射的成像
It's much better than what your hospital did.
是比你醫院做的好很多
And not only your quality is better
而且不但是你這樣品質比較好
And the Radiation of that Dose will be relatively low
而且那個Dose這個Radiation還會比較低
Even without this comparison
即使不用這個相對比
Then it should be better compared to it
那加上相對比它的效果應該會更好
then i know that means
那我知道就是說
the only reason that says
那唯一的原因說
why not do it in sync
為什麼不在同步輔射做
that is
就是說
no doctor will
沒有一個醫生會
just say ok
會就說OK
You want to make an aluminum anti-photography
你想要做一個鋁防攝影
Okay, I'll take you to the synchrony
好 送你到同步輔射
we are laughing
我們在笑說
Synchro
他到同步輔射
It looks like a factory inside
一看裡面跟工廠一樣
he was scared to death
他嚇就嚇死了
So many Americans they were in
那很多美國他們當初在
when doing a job like this
做這樣子的工作的時候
They have to get a special room
他們都要特別弄一間房間
There's going to be classical music in there
裡面要放古典音樂
people come in to make you comfortable
人進來讓你很舒服的
can feel
可以感覺
But what they do is a small amount of testing
但是他們做的都是小量的測試
just to prove that
就證明是說
Synchronous auxiliary radiation as long as the light source is good enough
同步輔射只要光源夠好
can definitely do this
絕對可以做這個事
but you get rid of God
但是你除天去把
Simultaneous shooting can say think of the way
同步輔射能夠說想到方式
go to the hospital
到醫院裡面去
Otherwise, this thing does not have much medical value
否則這個東西沒有太多的這個醫用價值
I don't ask for advice
我不請教一下
I am a doctor at National Taiwan University
我是台大的醫生
I study abroad Hover
我留學Hover
Now is the era of Nano technology
那現在是Nano technology的時代
everything is nano
everything is nano
The actual problem is that
那實際的問題就是說
which hospital can use this
哪一個醫院有用這個
Is there a Nano Machine now?
現在有Nano的Machine嗎
There's none
沒有嗎
now we are doing the same
現在我們現在在做一樣做
My son is a thoracic surgeon
我兒子是胸腔外科
related factories
相關廠的都會
opened by son
兒子開的
This morning also opened the way
今天早上也是在開道
that is
就是說
you are good
你這個是很好
very good idea
idea非常好
Did it actually come out?
那有沒有實際已經有出來
which hospital has it?
哪一個醫院有嗎
There's none
沒有嗎
we mean now
我們就是說現在
None of the hospitals are using
沒有一個醫院在用
So this is what I say
所以這個是我就說
if you have to wait today
如果今天要等
but no one is doing it
但是不是沒有人在做
several important companies
幾家重要的公司
G. Phillips Siemens
G. Phillips Siemens
They all have a research team to do this
他們都有研究的團隊來做這個事
The reason everyone gets stuck
大家卡到的理由
The technical bottleneck is the same
技術瓶頸是一樣的
It means I don't have a good enough light source
就是說我沒有夠好的光源
Who can you share with today
今天如果和誰可以把
we had thought
我們當初有想過
It is said that someone is selling this small copper cloth radiation
是說有人在賣這種小的這個銅布輻射
We also talked to the hospital
我們也跟醫院談過
For example, when I was with
比如說我跟那時候
Talked to this dean on Ma Street
跟馬街的這個院長談過
He said that if one or two million dollars
他說如果一兩百萬美金
not too important to them
對他們來講不是太重要
Because of the hospital
因為醫院的這個
can be recycled
都可以回收的
He just sees how many years you pay back
他只是看你多少年回本
You just have to make sure he's better
你只要確定他會比較好
we are sure of this
這個我們很確定
then he can be placed in the hospital
然後他可以放在醫院
they can operate
他們可以操作
Doctors don't treat patients
醫生不會把病人
send it elsewhere
送去別的地方做影像
He said I have a healing device today
他說我今天有一個治療的設備
I want to do politics
我要做政治治
to do this pointed therapy
要做這個直指治療
Yes there is a place in Taiwan
可以台灣有一個地方
or to the United States
或者到美國
Some people sent to the United States for treatment
有人就送到美國去治
no problem
這都沒有問題
I can't do video
做影像做不到
That's what we've been doing
那這個是我們一直在
Then these big companies are doing it
那這些大公司他們都在做
did not give up
也沒有放棄
It means that there is still hope for this thing
就表示說這個東西還有希望
Then we mentioned it again recently
那我們最近又在提了
This matter is that the Taiwan government began to support
這個事就是台灣政府開始有在支援
That is to say, I hope Taiwan will do digital S-light
就是說希望台灣做數位S光
something different
有一些不一樣的東西
then we mentioned this
那我們提了這個
And now there is also a company
而且現在也有一家公司
He bought a Swiss brand called Sweet Straight
他買了一個瑞士的品牌叫Sweet Straight
This is the chairman of Beiyi
這是北一的董事長
Li Zhude and the others went to buy it.
李主德他們去買下來的
they want if they evaluate
他們希望如果他們評估說
this thing can do
這個東西可以做
Then this may be what they will
那這個可能就是他們會
Then let's say our problem today is
那我們就說我們今天的問題是
this dose is too low
這個劑量太低
not too high
不是太高的問題
but I am now this
而是我現在這個
Buy a small one of this Micro Focus Source
買一個小的這個Micro Focus Source
it's good enough
它品質夠好
But its Power is too low
但是它的Power太低
You want us to buy a Micro Focus Source
你想我們買一個Micro Focus Source
It's not yet
它還不到
it may be 0. a few watts
它可能是0.幾瓦
so you have to take a chest photo
所以你要照一個胸腔照片
you have to take 30 seconds
你要照30秒
Then there is no resolution
那就沒有解析度可以
no resolution required
不需要什麼解析度
Human movement, breathing, and heartbeat are useless
人動的 呼吸 心跳都沒有用
So we're going to take this one
所以我們要把這一個
strength pulls it back
強度把它拉回來
but on the other hand
但是另外一方面
because we're going to talk now
因為我們現在來講說
If I do joints
我如果做做關節啦
Let's move in
做做入房啦
you talk to this woman
你跟這個婦女講說
just be patient
你稍微忍耐一下
stay a little longer
多待一會兒
it might still be possible
這可能還可以做得到
That chest can't help
那胸腔是沒辦法
because you actually told you not to breathe
因為你其實叫你不要呼吸
your heartbeat these
你心跳這些
you will vibrate
你會震動
So this is the only difficulty we know of
所以這個是我們知道目前唯一的困難
So there is a lot of development on S3
所以有很多關於S3的development
That is to say, this is done by physical people.
就是說這個是物理的人在做的
If this is done today
今天這個做出來的話
This will go to the market
這個才會到市場去
any left
還有沒有
may i ask
可以請教一下嗎
What is the difference between the so-called winding design imaging and the board design imaging?
所謂的繞設成像跟膳設成像是有什麼差異
Thanks
謝謝
OK
OK
Around the imaging tracking device
繞設成像跟膳設
In fact, these two are defraction in English.
這兩個其實這個就是英文是defraction
with Sketch
跟Sketch
Actually we are doing H3
其實我們在做H3
We still don't know exactly
我們到現在還其實不太清楚到底
These two images are actually talking about
這兩個成像其實在講的
if i say i'm talking
我如果說在講
We do image restoration
我們做成像還原
Actually one thing
其實講的一件事
Because when we're doing imaging
因為我們在做成像的時候
is the intensity that will emit all the S light
是會把所有的S光出來的強度
absorb it all
通通吸收
I can use a negative
我用一個底片也好
I can use a camera
我用一個照相機也好
get out
弄出來
But now I say for example
可是我現在譬如說
Unfortunately I didn't
可惜我沒有
For example, when you hit an object with an S light
譬如說你當一個S光打到一個物體的時候
look at the light it emits
你看它散出來的光
You can't find its connection above
你上面找不出它的關聯
so their progress
所以他們的進展
Now these S lights
現在這些S光
they can handle
他們能夠處理到
restore it to the way you were
把它還原成你原來這個樣子
So this includes
所以這個裡面就包括了
Intensity of scattered diffraction and scattered S light
散射的繞射跟散射的S光的強度
so if you ask
所以你要問的話
That is to say, what is the difference between this and the direct image?
就是說這個跟直接的影像有什麼差別
what we were talking about
我們現在剛剛在講的
Radiology means
radiology是說
I just pass through
我S光穿過去
I'm directly behind the image
我就在後面直接呈像
I don't see it diverge
我不看它這個發散
Diverge directly
直接發散
We may when you are doing this radiology in the hospital
我們可能你在醫院做這個 radiology的時候
You also have to use this grid to divert these S-Proong
你還要用 this grid 把這些發散的這個 S-prong
Detaly absorb
都吸收掉
Don't make the image blurred
你不要讓影像變得模糊
You just need to see it straight through it
你只要看它直直通過的
These two are the main differences
那這兩個是有主要的不一樣
That is almost useless to do with medium
那 Diffusion Imaging 在做 Medical 幾乎沒有用
Because of this needed this destensity
因為它的這個需要的這個 Intensity
The most important use of this is to be able to make about one structure
這個最重要的用途是希望能夠做大概一支結構
That is to say, I do nt grow the protein into a crystal today
就是說我今天我把蛋白質不要長成晶體
I put it in the water capacity and spray it in this light
我放在水水容量裡面噴到這個光裡面去
I solved the protein structure
我就把蛋白質結構解了
But just say modern
但是就是說現代
This is why this world spends so much money
這個也是為什麼這個全世界花這麼多錢
Each of this free electronic machine is spent all the light
這每一個這個自由電子這個機光都花的
They are close to one billion US dollars
都是接近十億美金
The United States spent about 100 million
美國都大概花了十億
Europe is one billion euro
歐洲都是十億歐元
One billion euro
One billion euro
This costs so much
這花這麼多錢
The only goal you told them to solve this
你叫他們他們其實唯一的目標是解這個
Membrane
Membrane
this protein this membrane protein
這個蛋白質這個膜蛋白
Because this thing can't be used
因為這個東西沒有辦法用
Most membrane proteins cannot be borrowed
大部分的膜蛋白沒有辦法做成借金來借
so this thing is very important
所以這個東西非常重要
So everyone is willing to spend the money
所以變成大家願意花這個錢
But its usefulness will not be
但是它的用處不會是
Otherwise like this strong
否則就像這麼強的
We can say that we can also go to therapy
我們可以說我們也可以去做治療
let's go in
我們這個進去
It is possible to enter this Pulse
它這一個Pulse進去可能
Everything around you is destroyed
你這附近的地方全部都摧毀了
But this is not for this do this
但是這個不是為了這個做這個
OK
OK
Eh
欸
Then I surrounded this picture of mine and you have not told you
那我對我這張圖圍你已經不告訴你
See how it works from here
從這裡看到是怎麼成正常的
no it's not
沒有這個其實不是
This is the normal lung
這個就是一般的這個肺的
This is a pig lung cannon
這個是豬的一個肺炮
Inside it is its organ
它這裡面是它的這個器管
Then we just because the picture is pretty
然後我們只是因為這個圖圍還蠻漂亮的
Back to what I just said
那回到剛剛就說
because of your lungs
因為你肺炮
because we relax the resolution
因為我們把解析度放鬆
Just wanted to see the resolution of the whole
剛剛像要看全數的這個解析度
actually not
其實不是
But you can zoom in you at that time if you watch him with our best resolution
但是你可以zoom in 你當時你如果把他用我們最好的解析度看的話
probably like this
大概就是這樣這樣
At this time, you can see the lung cannons accumulated one by one
這時候你就可以看到一個一個的肺炮累積在一起
So its actually the solution because the lung cannon has to hit dozens of microns
所以其實是解因為這肺炮都要打了幾十micron
So resolution is not an issue
所以解析度不是問題
This is just for show
這個只是要秀這個的原因
But at this resolution, you can't ask for live
但是在這種解析度你就不可能要求是在活體
I think Dr. Hu gave us a wonderful and simple explanation today.
我想胡博士今天給我們很精彩而且深入淺出
So everyone gets something
所以大家都有收穫
i think he is tired too
我想他也累了
everybody look
各位看
then we thank him very much today
那我們今天非常謝謝他
Thank you all
也謝謝大家的
you
you